<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Art Journey</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="learn">Learn</string>
    <string name="gallery">Gallery</string>
    <string name="title_activity_learn_screen">Timeline</string>
    <string name="title_activity_gallery_screen">Gallery</string>
    <string name="title_activity_slider_game">SliderGameActivity</string>
    <string name="Play_Game">Play Game</string>
    <string name="title_activity_mastermind">MastermindActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_show_picture_ar">showPictureAR</string>
    <string name="title_activity_find_differences_game">findDifferencesGame</string>
    <string name="title_activity_theory_menu">Library</string>
    <string name="title_activity_memory_activity">MemoryActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_color_picker">ColorPickerActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_grid_game">GridGameActivity</string>
    <string name="info_settings">Info</string>


    <string name="theory_0_0">The Renaissance  is a period from the 14th to the 17th century, considered the bridge between theMiddle Ages and modern history. It started as a cultural movement in Italy in the Late Medieval period and later spread to the rest of Europe. \n\t The word Renaissance, literally meaning \"Rebirth\" in French, first appears in English in the 1830s. The word occurs in Jules Michelet\'s 1855 work, Histoire de France. \n\t The Renaissance marks the period of European history at the close of the Middle Ages and the rise of the Modern world. It represents a cultural rebirth from the 14th through the middle of the 17th centuries. Early Renaissance, mostly in Italy, bridges the art period during the fifteenth century, between the Middle Ages and the High Renaissance in Italy. It is generally known that Renaissance matured in Northern Europe later, in the 16th century. One of the distinguishing features of Renaissance art was its development of highly realistic linear perspective. Giotto di Bondone (1267–1337) is credited with first treating a painting as a window into space. \n\t The development of perspective was part of a wider trend towards realism in the arts. To that end, painters also developed other techniques, studying light, shadow, and, famously in the case of Leonardo da Vinci, human anatomy. Underlying these changes in artistic method, was a renewed desire to depict the beauty of nature, and to unravel the axioms of aesthetics, with the works of Leonardo, Michelangelo and Raphael representing artistic pinnacles that were to be much imitated by other artists. \n\t Many works of Renaissance art depicted religious images, including subjects such as the Virgin Mary, or Madonna, and were encountered by contemporary audiences of the period in the context of religious rituals. Today, they are viewed as great works of art, but at the time they were seen and used mostly as devotional objects. Many Renaissance works were painted as altarpieces for incorporation into rituals associated with Catholic Mass and donated by patrons who sponsored the Mass itself.</string>
    <string name="title_0_0">The Renaissance</string>

    <string name="theory_0_3">Leonardo di ser Piero da Vinci (15 April 1452 – 2 May 1519) was an Italian polymath, painter, sculptor, architect, musician, mathematician, engineer, inventor, anatomist, geologist, cartographer, botanist, and writer. He is widely considered to be one of the greatest painters of all time and perhaps the most diversely talented person ever to have lived. His genius, perhaps more than that of any other figure, epitomized the Renaissance humanist ideal. Leonardo has often been described as the archetype of the Renaissance Man, a man of \"unquenchable curiosity\" and \"feverishly inventive imagination\".\n\t Leonardo was, and is, renowned primarily as a painter. Among his works, the Mona Lisa is the most famous and most parodied portrait and The Last Supper the most reproduced religious painting of all time, with their fame approached only by Michelangelo\'s The Creation of Adam. Leonardo\'s drawing of the Vitruvian Man is also regarded as a cultural icon, being reproduced on items as varied as the euro coin, textbooks, and T-shirts. Perhaps fifteen of his paintings have survived, the small number because of his constant, and frequently disastrous, experimentation with new techniques. Nevertheless, these few works, together with his notebooks, which contain drawings, scientific diagrams, and his thoughts on the nature of painting, compose a contribution to later generations of artists rivalled only by that of his contemporary, Michelangelo. \n\tLeonardo is revered for his technological ingenuity. He conceptualised flying machines, an armoured vehicle, concentrated solar power, an adding machine, and the double hull, also outlining a rudimentary theory of plate tectonics. He made substantial discoveries in anatomy, civil engineering, optics, and hydrodynamics, but he did not publish his findings and they had no direct influence on later science.</string>
    <string name="title_0_3">Leonardo da Vinci</string>

    <string name="theory_0_1">The Mona Lisa is a half-length portrait of a woman by the Italian artist Leonardo da Vinci, which has been acclaimed as \"the best known, the most visited, the most written about, the most sung about, the most parodied work of art in the world\".\n\tThe title of the painting, which is known in English as Mona Lisa, comes from a description by Renaissance art historian Giorgio Vasari, who wrote \"Leonardo undertook to paint, for Francesco del Giocondo, the portrait of Mona Lisa, his wife.\" Mona in Italian is a polite form of address originating as ma donna – similar to Ma’am, Madam, or my lady in English. This became madonna, and its contraction mona.  \n\tLeonardo da Vinci began painting the Mona Lisa in 1503 or 1504 in Florence, Italy. In 1516, Leonardo was invited by King François I to work at the Clos Lucé near the king\'s castle in Amboise. It is believed that he took the Mona Lisa with him and continued to work after he moved to France. Art historian Carmen C. Bambach has concluded that da Vinci probably continued refining the work until 1516 or 1517. On his death the painting was inherited, among other works, by his pupil and assistant Salaì. The king bought the painting for 4,000 écus and kept it at Palace of Fontainebleau. After the French Revolution, it was moved to the Louvre where it is now on permanent display.\n\t The painting was among the first portraits to depict the sitter before an imaginary landscape and Leonardo was one of the first painters to use aerial perspective. Leonardo used a pyramid design to place the woman simply and calmly in the space of the painting. Her folded hands form the front corner of the pyramid. Her breast, neck and face glow in the same light that models her hands. The light gives the variety of living surfaces an underlying geometry of spheres and circles. Leonardo referred to a seemingly simple formula for seated female figure: the images of seated Madonna, which were widespread at the time. He effectively modified this formula in order to create the visual impression of distance between the sitter and the observer.</string>
    <string name="title_0_1">Mona Lisa</string>

    <string name="theory_0_2">The Last Supper  is a late 15th-century mural painting by Leonardo da Vinci in the refectory of the Convent of Santa Maria delle Grazie, Milan. It is one of the world\'s most famous paintings, and one of the most studied, scrutinized, and satirized.\n\tThe work is presumed to have been commenced around 1495 and was commissioned as part of a plan of renovations to the church and its convent buildings by Leonardo\'s patron Ludovico Sforza, Duke of Milan. The painting represents the scene of The Last Supper of Jesus with his disciples, as it is told in the Gospel of John, 13:21. Leonardo has depicted the consternation that occurred among the Twelve Disciples when Jesus announced that one of them would betray him.\n\tThe Last Supper specifically portrays the reaction given by each apostle when Jesus said one of them would betray him. All twelve apostles have different reactions to the news, with various degrees of anger and shock. The apostles are identified from a manuscript (The Notebooks of Leonardo da Vinci p. 232) with their names found in the 19th century. (Before this, only Judas, Peter, John and Jesus were positively identified.)</string>
    <string name="title_0_2">The Last Supper</string>

    <string name="theory_0_6">Michelangelo di Lodovico Buonarroti Simoni (6 March 1475 – 18 February 1564), commonly known as Michelangelo, was an Italian sculptor, painter, architect, poet, and engineer of the High Renaissance who exerted an unparalleled influence on the development of Western art. Considered as the greatest living artist in his lifetime, he has since been held as one of the greatest artists of all time. Despite making few forays beyond the arts, his versatility in the disciplines he took up was of such a high order that he is often considered a contender for the title of the archetypal Renaissance man, along with his fellow Italian Leonardo da Vinci.\n\tA number of his works in painting, sculpture, and architecture rank among the most famous in existence. His output in every field during his long life was prodigious; when the sheer volume of correspondence, sketches, and reminiscences that survive is also taken into account, he is the best-documented artist of the 16th century.\n\tTwo of his best-known works, the Pietà and David, were sculpted before he turned thirty. Despite his low opinion of painting, Michelangelo also created two of the most influential works in fresco in the history of Western art: the scenes from Genesis on the ceiling and The Last Judgment on the altar wall of the Sistine Chapel in Rome. In a demonstration of Michelangelo\'s unique standing, he was the first Western artist whose biography was published while he was alive.\n\tMichelangelo, with Leonardo da Vinci and Raphael, is one of the three giants of the Florentine High Renaissance. Although their names are often cited together, Michelangelo was younger than Leonardo by 23 years, and older than Raphael by eight. Because of his reclusive nature, he had little to do with either artist and outlived both of them by more than forty years. Michelangelo took few sculpture students.\n\tArtists who were directly influenced by Michelangelo include Raphael, who imitated Michelangelo\'s prophets in two of his works, including his depiction of the great master in the School of Athens. Other artists, such as Pontormo, drew on the writhing forms of the Last Judgement and the frescoes of the Capella Paolina.</string>
    <string name="title_0_6">Michelangelo</string>

    <string name="theory_0_4">The Sistine Chapel ceiling, painted by Michelangelo between 1508 and 1512, is a cornerstone work of High Renaissance art. The ceiling\'s various painted elements form part of a larger scheme of decoration within the Chapel, which includes the large fresco The Last Judgment on the sanctuary wall, also by Michelangelo, wall paintings by several leading painters of the late 15th century including Sandro Botticelli, Domenico Ghirlandaio and Pietro Perugino, and a set of large tapestries by Raphael, the whole illustrating much of the doctrine of the Catholic Church.\n\tCentral to the ceiling decoration are nine scenes from the Book of Genesis of which The Creation of Adam is the best known, having an iconic standing equalled only by Leonardo da Vinci\'s Mona Lisa, the hands of God and Adam being reproduced in countless imitations. The complex design includes several sets of individual figures, both clothed and nude, which allowed Michelangelo to fully demonstrate his skill in creating a huge variety of poses for the human figure, and have provided an enormously influential pattern book of models for other artists ever since. \n\tThe narrative elements of the ceiling illustrate that God made the World as a perfect creation and put humanity into it, that humanity fell into disgrace and was punished by death and by separation from God. Humanity then sank further into sin and disgrace, and was punished by the Great Flood. Through a lineage of Ancestors – from Abraham to Joseph – God sent the saviour of humanity, Christ Jesus. The coming of the Saviour was prophesied by Prophets of Israel and Sibyls of the Classical world. The various components of the ceiling are linked to this Christian doctrine. Traditionally, the Old Testament was perceived as a prefiguring of the New Testament. Many incidents and characters of the Old Testament were commonly understood as having a direct symbolic link to some particular aspect of the life of Jesus or to an important element of Christian doctrine or to a sacrament such as Baptism or the Eucharist. Jonah, for example was readily recognisable by his attribute of the large fish, and was commonly seen to symbolised Jesus\' death and resurrection.</string>
    <string name="title_0_4">Ceiling of Sistine Chapel</string>

    <string name="theory_0_5">David is a masterpiece of Renaissance sculpture created between 1501 and 1504, by Michelangelo.\n\tIt is a 4.34-metre, 5.17-metre with the base marble statue of a standing male nude. The statue represents the Biblical hero David, a favoured subject in the art of Florence.Originally commissioned as one of a series of statues of prophets to be positioned along the roofline of the east end of Florence Cathedral, the statue was placed instead in a public square, outside the Palazzo della Signoria, the seat of civic government in Florence, where it was unveiled on 8 September 1504.\n\tBecause of the nature of the hero it represented, the statue soon came to symbolize the defense of civil liberties embodied in the Republic of Florence, an independent city-state threatened on all sides by more powerful rival states and by the hegemony of the Medici family. The eyes of David, with a warning glare, were turned towards Rome.\n\tThe statue appears to show David after he has made the decision to fight Goliath but before the battle has actually taken place, a moment between conscious choice and action. The statue is a Renaissance interpretation of a common ancient Greek theme of the standing heroic male nude. In the High Renaissance, contrapposto poses were thought of as a distinctive feature of antique sculpture. This is typified in David, as the figure stands with one leg holding its full weight and the other leg forward. This classic pose causes the figure’s hips and shoulders to rest at opposing angles, giving a slight s-curve to the entire torso. The contrapposto is emphasised by the turn of the head to the left, and by the contrasting positions of the arms. Michelangelo’s David has become one of the most recognized works of Renaissance sculpture, a symbol of strength and youthful beauty. It was the colossal size of the statue that impressed most of Michelangelo\'s contemporaries, however. some described it as \"certainly a miracle that of Michelangelo, to restore to life one who was dead,\".</string>
    <string name="title_0_5">David</string>

    <string name="theory_0_9">Raffaello Sanzio da Urbino(April 6 or March 28, 1483 – April 6, 1520), known as Raphael, was an Italian painter and architect of the High Renaissance. His work is admired for its clarity of form, ease of composition, and visual achievement of the Neoplatonic ideal of human grandeur. Together with Michelangelo and Leonardo da Vinci, he forms the traditional trinity of great masters of that period. Raphael was enormously productive, running an unusually large workshop and, despite his death at 37, leaving a large body of work.\n\tThe best known work is The School of Athens in the Vatican Stanza della Segnatura. After his early years in Rome much of his work was executed by his workshop from his drawings, with considerable loss of quality. He was extremely influential in his lifetime, though outside Rome his work was mostly known from his collaborative printmaking. After his death, the influence of his great rival Michelangelo was more widespread until the 18th and 19th centuries, when Raphael\'s more serene and harmonious qualities were again regarded as the highest models.\n\tRaphael was highly admired by his contemporaries, although his influence on artistic style in his own century was less than that of Michelangelo. Mannerism, beginning at the time of his death, and later the Baroque, took art \"in a direction totally opposed\" to Raphael\'s qualities \"with Raphael\'s death, classic art – the High Renaissance – subsided.\n\tRaphael was one of the finest draftsmen in the history of Western art, and used drawings extensively to plan his compositions. According to a near-contemporary, when beginning to plan a composition, he would lay out a large number of stock drawings of his on the floor, and begin to draw \"rapidly\", borrowing figures from here and there. This is how Raphael himself, who was so rich in inventiveness, used to work, always coming up with four or six ways to show a narrative, each one different from the rest, and all of them full of grace and well done.</string>
    <string name="title_0_9">Raphael</string>

    <string name="theory_0_7">The School of Athens, or Scuola di Atene in Italian, is one of the most famous frescoes by the Italian Renaissance artist Raphael. It was painted between 1509 and 1511 as a part of Raphael\'s commission to decorate the rooms now known as the Stanze di Raffaello, in the Apostolic Palace in the Vatican. The picture has long been seen as \"Raphael\'s masterpiece and the perfect embodiment of the classical spirit of the Renaissance.\n\tThe School of Athens represents all the greatest mathematicians, philosophers and scientists from classical antiquity gathered together sharing their ideas and learning from each other. These figures all lived at different times, but here they are gathered together under one roof. The identities of some of the philosophers in the picture, such as Plato or Aristotle, are certain. Beyond that, identifications of Raphael’s figures have always been hypothetical. Those who can be identified with some certainty are Plato, Aristotle, Socrates, Pythagoras, Euclid, Ptolemy, Zoroaster, Raphael, Sodoma and Diogenes. Other identifications are more or less speculative.\n\tIn the center of the fresco, at its architecture\'s central vanishing point, are the two undisputed main subjects: Plato on the left and Aristotle, his student, on the right. Both figures hold modern (of the time), bound copies of their books in their left hands, while gesturing with their right. Plato holds Timaeus, Aristotle his Nicomachean Ethics. Plato is depicted as old, grey, wise-looking, and bare-foot. By contrast Aristotle, slightly ahead of him, is in mature manhood, handsome, well-shod and dressed with gold, and the youth about them seem to look his way. Plato points up and Aristotle holds his hand down. It is popularly thought that their gestures indicate central aspects of their philosophies and divergence of the two philosophical schools. Plato argues a sense of timelessness whilst Aristotle looks into the physicality of life and the present realm.</string>
    <string name="title_0_7">School of Athens</string>

    <string name="theory_0_8">Sistine Madonna, also called La Madonna di San Sisto, is an oil painting by the Italian artist Raphael. Commissioned in 1512 by Pope Julius II as an altarpiece for the church of San Sisto, Piacenza, it was one of the last Madonnas painted by the artist. Relocated to Dresden from 1754, the well-known painting has been particularly influential in Germany. After World War II, it was relocated to Moscow for a decade before it was returned to Germany. There, it resides as one of the central pieces in the Gemäldegalerie Alte Meister. In the painting the Madonna, holding the Christ Child and flanked by Saint Sixtus and Saint Barbara, stands on clouds before dozens of obscured cherubs, while two distinctive winged cherubs rest on their elbows beneath her.\n\tOne of the artist\'s last Madonnas, the painting was commissioned by Pope Julius II in 1512 in honor of his late uncle, Pope Sixtus IV, as an altarpiece for the Benedictine basilica of the Monastery of San Sisto, Piacenza, a church with which the Rovere family had a long-standing relationship. It was their requirement that the image contain both Saint Sixtus and Saint Barbara. Legend has it that when Antonio da Correggio first laid eyes on the piece, he was inspired to cry, \"And I also, I am a painter!\"\n\tA prominent element within the painting, the winged angels beneath Mary are famous in their own right. As early as 1913 famous critics declared that \"no cherub or group of cherubs is so famous as the two that lean on the altar top indicated at the very bottom of the picture.\" Heavily marketed, they have been featured in stamps, postcards, T-shirts, and wrapping paper. These cherubim have inspired legends of their own. According to a 1912 article in Fra Magazine, when Raphael was painting the Madonna the children of his model would come in to watch. Struck by their posture as they did, the story goes, he added them to the painting exactly as he saw them. Another story, recounted in 1912\'s St. Nicholas Magazine, says that Raphael rather was inspired by two children he encountered on the street when he saw them \"looking wistfully into the window of a baker\'s shop.\" prompting the neologism Sitonna.</string>
    <string name="title_0_8">Sistine Madonna</string>

    <string name="theory_0_11">Tiziano Vecelli or Tiziano Vecellio , known in English as Titian, was an Italian painter, the most important member of the 16th-century Venetian school.\n\tRecognized by his contemporaries as \"The Sun Amidst Small Stars\", Titian was one of the most versatile of Italian painters, equally adept with portraits, landscape backgrounds, and mythological and religious subjects. His painting methods, particularly in the application and use of color, would exercise a profound influence not only on painters of the Italian Renaissance, but on future generations of Western art.\n\tDuring the course of his long life, Titian\'s artistic manner changed drastically but he retained a lifelong interest in color. Although his mature works may not contain the vivid, luminous tints of his early pieces, their loose brushwork and subtlety of tone are without precedent in the history of Western painting. He was noted for his mastery of colour.</string>
    <string name="title_0_11">Titian</string>

    <string name="theory_0_10">Assumption of the Virgin is a large oil painting by Italian Renaissance artist Titian, executed in 1516–1518. It is located on the high altar in the Basilica di Santa Maria Gloriosa dei Frari in Venice, being the largest altarpiece in the city.\n\tThe Assumption of the Virgin was Titian\'s first major commission in Venice. He soon became the lead painter of Venice. Breaking tradition with its heroic character scale and trademark color, its twisted Virgin and dramatically gesturing apostles disturbed passersby. When Titian placed this giant painting in its majestic marble frame, it garnered much attention. It was deemed worth noting by the Venetian diarist, Marino Sanuto the Younger, who wrote, \"May 20, 1518: Yesterday the panel painted by Titian for … the Minorites was put up.\n\tThe Assumption of the virgin depicted in the painting is celebrated every year on August 15 and is a defined dogma of the Catholic church. It commemorates the rising of Mary to heaven before the decay of her body. It is a sign of her passing into eternal life and thus, it is a holy day of obligation. There is a distinction between the ascension of Jesus and the assumption of Mary. The ascension was the rising of Jesus under his own power, while the assumption means that someone else raised Mary to heaven. It is said that Jesus himself came and carried her up. This picture shows different events in three layers. In the lowest layer are the Apostles. They are shown in a variety of poses, ranging from gazing in awe, to kneeling and reaching for the skies. In the center, the Virgin Mary is drawn wrapped in a red robe and blue mantle. She is raised to the heavens by a swarm of cherubim while standing on a cloud. Above is an attempt to draw God, who watches over the earth with hair flying in the wind. Next to him, flies an angel with a crown for Mary.</string>
    <string name="title_0_10">Assumption of the Virgin</string>

    <string name="theory_0_12">The Birth of Venus (Italian: Nascita di Venere) is a painting by Sandro Botticelli generally thought to have been painted in the mid 1480s. The iconography of Birth of Venus is similar to a description of the event (or rather, a description of a sculpture of the event) in a poem by Angelo Poliziano, the Stanze per la giostra. However, no single text provides the precise imagery of the painting.\n\tFor Plato – and so for the members of the Florentine Platonic Academy – Venus had two aspects: she was an earthly goddess who aroused humans to physical love or she was a heavenly goddess who inspired intellectual love in them. Plato further argued that contemplation of physical beauty allowed the mind to better understand spiritual beauty. So, looking at Venus, the most beautiful of goddesses, might at first raise a physical response in viewers which then lifted their minds towards the godly. A Neoplatonic reading of Botticelli\'s Birth of Venus suggests that 15th-century viewers would have looked at the painting and felt their minds lifted to the realm of divine love.</string>
    <string name="title_0_12">The Birth of Venus</string>

    <string name="theory_1_0">The Baroque is often thought of as a period of artistic style that used exaggerated motion and clear, easily interpreted detail to produce drama, tension, exuberance, and grandeur in sculpture, painting, architecture, literature, dance, theater, and music. The style began around 1600 in Rome, Italy, and spread to most of Europe.\n\tThe popularity and success of the Baroque style was encouraged by the Catholic Church, which had decided at the time of the Council of Trent, in response to the Protestant Reformation, that the arts should communicate religious themes in direct and emotional involvement.\n\tThe word baroque is derived from the Portuguese word \"barroco\", Spanish \"barroco\", or French \"baroque\", all of which refer to a \"rough or imperfect pearl\", though whether it entered those languages via Latin, Arabic, or some other source is uncertain.\n\tThe Baroque era is sometimes divided into roughly three phases for convenience:\n\n\t-	Early Baroque, c.1590–c.1625\n\t-	High Baroque, c.1625–c.1660\n\t-	Late Baroque, c.1660–c.1725\n\n\tLate Baroque is also sometimes used synonymously with the succeeding Rococo movement.\n\tBaroque style featured \"exaggerated lighting, intense emotions, release from restraint, and even a kind of artistic sensationalism\". Baroque art did not really depict the life style of the people at that time; however, \"closely tied to the Counter-Reformation, this style melodramatically reaffirmed the emotional depths of the Catholic faith and glorified both church and monarchy\" of their power and influence.</string>
    <string name="title_1_0">Baroque</string>

    <string name="theory_1_4">Michelangelo Merisi (or Amerighi) da Caravaggio (Milan, 29 September 1571 – 18 July 1610) was an Italian painter active in Rome, Naples, Malta, and Sicily between 1592 and 1610. His paintings, which combine a realistic observation of the human state, both physical and emotional, with a dramatic use of lighting, had a formative influence on Baroque painting.\n\tCaravaggio trained as a painter in Milan under Simone Peterzano who had himself trained under Titian. In his twenties Caravaggio moved to Rome where there was a demand for paintings to fill the many huge new churches and palazzos being built at the time. It was also a period when the Church was searching for a stylistic alternative to Mannerism in religious art that was tasked to counter the threat of Protestantism. Caravaggio\'s innovation was a radical naturalism that combined close physical observation with a dramatic, even theatrical, use of chiaroscuro which came to be known as tenebrism (the shift from light to dark with little intermediate value).\n\tCaravaggio \"put the oscuro (shadows) into chiaroscuro.\" Chiaroscuro was practiced long before he came on the scene, but it was Caravaggio who made the technique a dominant stylistic element, darkening the shadows and transfixing the subject in a blinding shaft of light. With this came the acute observation of physical and psychological reality which formed the ground both for his immense popularity and for his frequent problems with his religious commissions. He worked at great speed, from live models, scoring basic guides directly onto the canvas with the end of the brush handle; very few of Caravaggio\'s drawings appear to have survived, and it is likely that he preferred to work directly on the canvas.\n\tCaravaggio never married and had no known children, and Howard Hibbard notes the absence of erotic female figures from the artist\'s oeuvre: \"In his entire career he did not paint a single female nude.\" On the other hand, the cabinet-pieces from the Del Monte period are replete with \"full-lipped, languorous boys … who seem to solicit the onlooker with their offers of fruit, wine, flowers - and themselves.\"</string>
    <string name="title_1_4">Caravaggio</string>

    <string name="theory_1_1">Basket of Fruit (c.1599) is a painting by the Italian Baroque master Michelangelo Merisi da Caravaggio (1571–1610), which hangs in the Biblioteca Ambrosiana (Ambrosian Library), Milan.\n\t\n\nType: oil on canvas.\n\n\tIt shows a wicker basket perched on the edge of a ledge. The basket contains a selection of summer fruit.\n\tMuch has been made of the worm–eaten, insect–predated, and generally less than perfect condition of the fruit. Possibly Caravaggio simply painted what was available; or possibly it has some meaning along the general lines of \'all things decay\'; more specifically, there may be a reference to the Book of Amos 8:1–2: \"This is what the Lord God showed me — a basket of summer fruit. He said, \"Amos, what do you see\?\" And I said, \"A basket of summer fruit.\" Then the Lord God said to me, \"The end has come upon my people Israel; I will never again pass them by.\" (God is angry with Israel for neglecting the poor, and there may be a pun in Hebrew between \'basket of fruit\' and \'the end\').</string>
    <string name="title_1_1">Basket of Fruit</string>

    <string name="theory_1_3">The Young Sick Bacchus (Italian: Bacchino Malato), also known as the Sick Bacchus or the Self-Portrait as Bacchus, is an early self-portrait by the Baroque artist Michelangelo Merisi da Caravaggio, dated between 1593 and 1594. It now hangs in the Galleria Borghese in Rome. According to Caravaggio\'s first biographer, Giovanni Baglione, it was a cabinet piece painted by the artist using a mirror.\n\nType: oil on canvas.\n\n\tSources for this period are inconclusive and probably inaccurate, but they agree that at one point the artist fell extremely ill and spent six months in the hospital of Santa Maria della Consolazione. According to a 2009 article in the American medical publication Clinical Infectious Diseases, the painting indicates that Caravaggio\'s physical ailment likely involved malaria, as the jaundiced appearance of the skin and the icterus in the eyes are indications of some active hepatic disease causing high levels of bilirubin.\n\tApart from its assumed autobiographical content, this early painting was likely used by Caravaggio to market himself, demonstrating his virtuosity in painting genres such as still-life and portraits and hinting at the ability to paint the classical figures of antiquity. The three-quarters angle of the face was among those preferred for late renaissance portraiture, but what is striking is the grimace and tilt of the head, and the very real sense of the suffering; a feature that most Baroque art shares.</string>
    <string name="title_1_3">Baccus</string>

    <string name="theory_1_2">Boy with a Basket of Fruit, c.1593, is a painting generally ascribed to Italian Baroque master Michelangelo Merisi da Caravaggio, currently in the Galleria Borghese, Rome.\n\nType: oil on canvas.\n\n\tThe painting dates from the time when Caravaggio, newly arrived in Rome from his native Milan, was making his way in the competitive Roman art world. The model was his friend and companion, the Sicilian painter Mario Minniti, at about 16 years old.\n\tAt one level the painting is a genre piece designed to demonstrate the artist\'s ability to depict everything from the skin of the boy to the skin of a peach, from the folds of the robe to the weave of the basket.</string>
    <string name="title_1_2">Boy with a Basket</string>

    <string name="theory_1_8">Sir Peter Paul Rubens (28 June 1577 – 30 May 1640) was a Flemish Baroque painter. A proponent of an extravagant Baroque style that emphasized movement, colour, and sensuality, Rubens is well known for his Counter-Reformation altarpieces, portraits, landscapes, and history paintings of mythological and allegorical subjects.\n\tRubens was a prolific artist. His commissioned works were mostly religious subjects, and \"history\" paintings, which included mythological subjects, and hunt scenes. He painted portraits, especially of friends, and self-portraits, and in later life painted several landscapes. Rubens designed tapestries and prints, as well as his own house.\n\tHis drawings are mostly extremely forceful but not overly detailed. His fondness of painting full-figured women gave rise to the terms \'Rubensian\' or \'Rubenesque\' for plus-sized women.\n\tPaintings from Rubens\' workshop can be divided into three categories: those he painted by himself, those he painted in part (mainly hands and faces), and those he only supervised as other painters produced them from his drawings or oil sketches.</string>
    <string name="title_1_8">Paul Rubens</string>

    <string name="theory_1_5">The Descent from the Cross, or Deposition of Christ, is the scene, as depicted in art, from the Gospels\' accounts of Joseph of Arimathea and Nicodemus taking Christ down from the cross after his crucifixion (John 19:38–42). In Byzantine art the topic became popular in the 9th century, and in the West from the 10th century. The Descent from the Cross is the 13th Station of the Cross.\n\tEven in early depictions the details and posing of the composition, and especially the position of Christ\'s body, are varied. The scene was usually included in medieval cycles of the Life or the Passion of Christ, between the Crucifixion and the Entombment of Christ. The Lamentation of Christ, or Pietà, showing the body of Christ held by Mary, may intervene between these two, and is common as an individual image, especially in sculpture. The Bearing of the body, showing Christ\'s body being carried to his tomb, and the Anointing of Christ\'s body, showing the body laid flat on the top of the tomb or a similarly-shaped \"anointing-stone\" are other scenes that may be shown. This last is especially important in Orthodox art, where it is shown on the Epitaphios.\n\tWith the Renaissance the subject became popular for altarpieces, partly because of the challenges of the composition, and the suitability of its vertical shape. It was painted several times by both Rubens and Rembrandt, who repeated one of his paintings (now in Munich) in a large print, his only one to be mainly engraved, as well as making two other etchings of the subject.</string>
    <string name="title_1_5">The Descent from the Cross</string>

    <string name="theory_1_6">Samson and Delilah is a painting by the Flemish Baroque painter Peter Paul Rubens (1577–1640). It dates from about 1609 to 1610.\n\nType: oil on wood\n\n\tThe painting depicts an episode from the Old Testament story of Samson and Delilah (Judges 16). Samson, having fallen in love with Delilah, tells her the secret of his great strength: his uncut hair. Rubens portrays the moment, when having fallen asleep on Delilah\'s lap, a servant proceeds to cut Samson\'s hair. After, a weakened Samson is arrested by Philistine soldiers. The soldiers can be seen in the right-hand background of the painting.\n\tThe niche behind Delilah contains a statue of the Venus, the Goddess of love and her son, Cupid. This can be taken to represent the cause of Samson\'s fate. The old woman standing behind her, providing further light for the scene, does not appear in the biblical narrative of Samson and Delilah. She is believed to be a procuress, and the adjacent profiles of her and Delilah may symbolise the old woman\'s past, and Delilah\'s future. The Philistine cutting Samson\'s hair has his hands crossed as he cuts, this is a sign of deceit.</string>
    <string name="title_1_6">Samson and Delilah</string>

    <string name="theory_1_7">Type: oil on canvas\n\n\tThe Hippopotamus and Crocodile Hunt is a large painting by Peter Paul Rubens, featuring the hunt on hippopotamus and crocodile with three hunting dogs. There is also a reference to a leopard in the pelt on the horse of the upper left rider. Rubens used the dramatics of diagonals to heighten the sense of immediacy and movement and redirected attention downward into the center of action.\n\tThe Hippopotamus and Crocodile Hunt is one of the four hunting paintings, commissioned by Maximilian I, Elector of Bavaria to decorate the old Schleissheim Palace. After the seizure of this cycle during the Napoleonic Wars only The Hippopotamus and Crocodile Hunt was returned to Munich. In the notice of January 25, 1847 Eugène Delacroix admired the crocodile as a \"masterpiece of execution\", remarking, however, that \"its action could have been more interesting\".</string>
    <string name="title_1_7">Hunt</string>

    <string name="theory_1_12">Rembrandt Harmenszoon van Rijn (15 July 1606[1] – 4 October 1669) was a Dutch painter and etcher. He is generally considered one of the greatest painters and printmakers in European art and the most important in Dutch history. His contributions to art came in a period of great wealth and cultural achievement that historians call the Dutch Golden Age when Dutch Golden Age painting, although in many ways antithetical to the Baroque style that dominated Europe, was extremely prolific and innovative, and gave rise to important new genres in painting.\n\tRembrandt\'s greatest creative triumphs are exemplified especially in his portraits of his contemporaries, self-portraits and illustrations of scenes from the Bible. His self-portraits form a unique and intimate biography, in which the artist surveyed himself without vanity and with the utmost sincerity.\n\tThroughout his career Rembrandt took as his primary subjects the themes of portraiture, landscape and narrative painting. For the last, he was especially praised by his contemporaries, who extolled him as a masterly interpreter of biblical stories for his skill in representing emotions and attention to detail.\n\tIt was during Rembrandt\'s Leiden period (1625–1631) that Lastman\'s influence was most prominent. It is also likely that at this time Lievens had a strong impact on his work as well. Paintings were rather small, but rich in details (for example, in costumes and jewelry). Religious and allegorical themes were favored, as were tronies.\n\tDuring his early years in Amsterdam (1632–1636), Rembrandt began to paint dramatic biblical and mythological scenes in high contrast and of large format seeking to emulate the baroque style of Rubens.\n\tBy the late 1630s Rembrandt had produced a few paintings and many etchings of landscapes. Often these landscapes highlighted natural drama, featuring uprooted trees and ominous skies.\n\tIn the decade following the Night Watch, Rembrandt\'s paintings varied greatly in size, subject, and style. The previous tendency to create dramatic effects primarily by strong contrasts of light and shadow gave way to the use of frontal lighting and larger and more saturated areas of color.\n\tIn the 1650s, Rembrandt\'s style changed again. Colors became richer and brush strokes more pronounced.</string>
    <string name="title_1_12">Rembrandt</string>

    <string name="theory_1_9">Philosopher in Meditation (Bredius 431) is the traditional title of an oil painting in the Musée du Louvre, Paris, that has long been attributed to the 17th-century Dutch artist Rembrandt.\n\nType: oil on oak\n\n\tThe painting depicts in slightly accelerated perspective two figures in a partially vaulted interior that is dominated by a wooden spiral staircase. The architecture includes stone, brick and wood, with arched elements (window, vault, doors) that create an impression of monumentality.\n\tThe presumed subject matter, the finely graded chiaroscuro treatment and intricate composition were widely appreciated in France and the painting is mentioned in the writings of many 19th- and 20th-century literary figures.\n\tOn the pre-iconographic level, this is one of the most \"graphic\" works painted by Rembrandt, in the sense that it contains many straight, curved, circular, and radiating lines: from the lines of the flagstones to those of the window, the bricks, the wainscotting, and of course the staircase. As in the staircase and the basketwork tray at the center of the composition, the curved lines can be said to organize the straight lines. As it is, the overall painting is quite dark due to the aging of the varnish.</string>
    <string name="title_1_9">Philosopher in Meditation</string>

    <string name="theory_1_11">The Anatomy Lesson of Dr. Nicolaes Tulp is a 1632 oil painting on canvas by Rembrandt housed in the Mauritshuis museum in The Hague, the Netherlands. Dr. Nicolaes Tulp is pictured explaining the musculature of the arm to medical professionals. Some of the spectators are various doctors who paid commissions to be included in the painting.\n\nType: oil on canvas\n\n\tThe event can be dated to 16 January 1632: the Amsterdam Guild of Surgeons, of which Tulp was official City Anatomist, permitted only one public dissection a year, and the body would have to be that of an executed criminal. The face of the corpse is partially shaded, a suggestion of umbra mortis (shadow of death), a technique that Rembrandt was to use frequently.\n\tAnatomy lessons were a social event in the 17th century, taking place in lecture rooms that were actual theatres, with students, colleagues and the general public being permitted to attend on payment of an entrance fee. The spectators are appropriately dressed for a solemn social occasion. It is thought that the uppermost (not holding the paper) and farthest left figures were added to the picture later.</string>
    <string name="title_1_11">The Anatomy Lesson</string>

    <string name="theory_1_10">Militia Company of District II under the Command of Captain Frans Banninck Cocq, also known as The Shooting Company of Frans Banning Cocq and Willem van Ruytenburch, but commonly referred to as The Night Watch (Dutch: De Nachtwacht), is a 1642 painting by Rembrandt van Rijn. The Night Watch is a world renowned example of Baroque art.\n\nType: oil on canvas\n\n\tThe painting is renowned for three characteristics: its colossal size (363 cm × 437 cm (11.91 ft × 14.34 ft)), the effective use of light and shadow (chiaroscuro), and the perception of motion in what would have traditionally been a static military portrait.\n\tIt depicts the eponymous company moving out, led by Captain Frans Banning Cocq (dressed in black, with a red sash) and his lieutenant, Willem van Ruytenburch (dressed in yellow, with a white sash). With effective use of sunlight and shade, Rembrandt leads the eye to the three most important characters among the crowd, the two gentlemen in the centre (from whom the painting gets its original title), and the small girl in the centre left background. Behind them, the company\'s colours are carried by the ensign, Jan Visscher Cornelissen.\n\tRembrandt has displayed the traditional emblem of the Arquebusiers in the painting in a natural way: the girl in yellow dress in the background is carrying the main symbols. She is a kind-of mascot herself: the claws of a dead chicken on her belt represent the clauweniers (arquebusiers); the pistol behind the chicken stands for \'clover\'; and, she is holding the militia\'s goblet. The man in front of her is wearing a helmet with an oak leaf, a traditional motif of the Arquebusiers. The dead chicken is also meant to represent a defeated adversary. The colour yellow is often associated with victory.</string>
    <string name="title_1_10">Militia Company</string>

    <string name="theory_1_16">Diego Rodríguez de Silva y Velázquez (baptized on June 6, 1599 – August 6, 1660) was a Spanish painter who was the leading artist in the court of King Philip IV and one of the most important painters of the Spanish Golden Age. He was an individualistic artist of the contemporary Baroque period, important as a portrait artist. In addition to numerous renditions of scenes of historical and cultural significance, he painted scores of portraits of the Spanish royal family, other notable European figures, and commoners, culminating in the production of his masterpiece Las Meninas (1656).\n\tFrom the first quarter of the nineteenth century, Velázquez\'s artwork was a model for the realist and impressionist painters, in particular Édouard Manet. Since that time, famous modern artists, including Pablo Picasso, Salvador Dalí and Francis Bacon, have paid tribute to Velázquez by recreating several of his most famous works.\n\tBesides the forty portraits of Philip by Velázquez, he painted portraits of other members of the royal family: Philip\'s first wife, Elisabeth of Bourbon, and her children, especially her eldest son, Don Baltasar Carlos, of whom there is a beautiful full-length in a private room at Buckingham Palace. Cavaliers, soldiers, churchmen, and the poet Francisco de Quevedo (now at Apsley House), sat for Velázquez.</string>
    <string name="title_1_16">Velázquez</string>

    <string name="theory_1_13">Las Meninas (Spanish for The Maids of Honour) is a 1656 painting by Diego Velázquez, the leading artist of the Spanish Golden Age, in the Museo del Prado in Madrid. The work\'s complex and enigmatic composition raises questions about reality and illusion, and creates an uncertain relationship between the viewer and the figures depicted. Because of these complexities, Las Meninas has been one of the most widely analyzed works in Western painting.\n\nType: oil on canvas\n\n\tThe painting shows a large room in the Royal Alcazar of Madrid during the reign of King Philip IV of Spain, and presents several figures, most identifiable from the Spanish court, captured, according to some commentators, in a particular moment as if in a snapshot. Some look out of the canvas towards the viewer, while others interact among themselves. The young Infanta Margaret Theresa is surrounded by her entourage of maids of honour, chaperone, bodyguard, two dwarfs and a dog. Just behind them, Velázquez portrays himself working at a large canvas. Velázquez looks outwards, beyond the pictorial space to where a viewer of the painting would stand. In the background there is a mirror that reflects the upper bodies of the king and queen. They appear to be placed outside the picture space in a position similar to that of the viewer, although some scholars have speculated that their image is a reflection from the painting Velázquez is shown working on.\n\tLas Meninas has long been recognised as one of the most important paintings in Western art history.</string>
    <string name="title_1_13">Las Meninas</string>

    <string name="theory_1_14">The Rokeby Venus (also known as The Toilet of Venus, Venus at her Mirror, Venus and Cupid, or La Venus del espejo) is a painting by Diego Velázquez (1599–1660), the leading artist of the Spanish Golden Age. Completed between 1647 and 1651, and probably painted during the artist\'s visit to Italy, the work depicts the goddess Venus in a sensual pose, lying on a bed and looking into a mirror held by the Roman god of physical love, her son Cupid. The painting is in the National Gallery, London.\n\tNumerous works, from the ancient to the baroque, have been cited as sources of inspiration for Velázquez. The nude Venuses of the Italian painters, such as Giorgione\'s Sleeping Venus (c. 1510) and Titian\'s Venus of Urbino (1538), were the main precedents. In this work, Velázquez combined two established poses for Venus: recumbent on a couch or a bed, and gazing at a mirror. She is often described as looking at herself on the mirror, although this is physically impossible since viewers can see her face reflected in their direction. This phenomenon is known as the Venus effect. In a number of ways the painting represents a pictorial departure, through its central use of a mirror, and because it shows the body of Venus turned away from the observer of the painting.\n\tThe Rokeby Venus is the only surviving female nude by Velázquez. Nudes were extremely rare in seventeenth-century Spanish art, which was policed actively by members of the Spanish Inquisition.</string>
    <string name="title_1_14">The Rokeby Venus</string>

    <string name="theory_1_15">La rendición de Breda (English: The Surrender of Breda, also known as El cuadro de las lanzas or Las lanzas) is a painting by the Spanish Golden Age painter Diego Velázquez. It was completed during the years 1634–35, inspired by Velázquez\'s visit to Italy with Ambrogio Spinola, the Genoese general who conquered Breda on June 5, 1625. It is considered one of Velázquez\'s best works. Jan Morris has called it \"one of the most Spanish of all pictures\".\n\nType: oil on canvas\n\n\tThe Surrender of Breda was one of twelve life-size battle scenes intended to perpetuate victories won by Philip IV’s armies that hung in the Salón de Reinos in Buen Retiro. It illustrates the exchange of keys that occurred three days after the capitulation between Spain and the Netherlands was signed on June 5, 1625. Hence, the focus of the painting is not on the battle itself, but rather the reconciliation. At the center of the painting, literally and figuratively, is the key given to Spinola by Justin of Nassau. The key is “the precise center of his design, [enclosing] it in an emphatic parallelogram so that it becomes the focus of the entire large canvas—literally the key to the composition, locking all other components into place.” This battle painting is notable for its static and sentimental qualities.</string>
    <string name="title_1_15">The Surrender of Breda</string>

    <string name="theory_2_0">Impressionism is a 19th-century art movement. Impressionist painting characteristics include relatively small, thin, yet visible brush strokes, open composition, emphasis on accurate depiction of light in its changing qualities (often accentuating the effects of the passage of time), ordinary subject matter, inclusion of movement as a crucial element of human perception and experience, and unusual visual angles.\n\tIt originated with a group of Paris-based artists. Their independent exhibitions brought them to prominence during the 1870s and 1880s, in spite of harsh opposition from the conventional art community in France. The name of the style derives from the title of a Claude Monet work, Impression, soleil levant (Impression, Sunrise).\n\tRadicals in their time, early Impressionists violated the rules of academic painting. They constructed their pictures from freely brushed colours that took precedence over lines and contours.\n\tThey also painted realistic scenes of modern life, and often painted outdoors. Previously, still lifes and portraits as well as landscapes were usually painted in a studio.[1] The Impressionists found that they could capture the momentary and transient effects of sunlight by painting en plein air. They portrayed overall visual effects instead of details, and used short \"broken\" brush strokes of mixed and pure unmixed colour—not blended smoothly or shaded, as was customary—to achieve an effect of intense colour vibration.\n\tImpressionism emerged in France at the same time that a number of other painters, including the Italian artists known as the Macchiaioli, and Winslow Homer in the United States, were also exploring plein-air painting. The Impressionists, however, developed new techniques specific to the style. Encompassing what its adherents argued was a different way of seeing, it is an art of immediacy and movement, of candid poses and compositions, of the play of light expressed in a bright and varied use of colour.\n\tThe public, at first hostile, gradually came to believe that the Impressionists had captured a fresh and original vision, even if the art critics and art establishment disapproved of the new style.\n\tBy recreating the sensation in the eye that views the subject, rather than delineating the details of the subject, and by creating a welter of techniques and forms, Impressionism is a precursor of various painting styles, including Neo-Impressionism, Post-Impressionism, Fauvism, and Cubism.</string>
    <string name="title_2_0">Impressionism</string>

    <string name="theory_2_3">Oscar-Claude Monet  14 November 1840 – 5 December 1926) was a founder of French Impressionist painting, and the most consistent and prolific practitioner of the movement\'s philosophy of expressing one\'s perceptions before nature, especially as applied to plein-air landscape painting. The term \"Impressionism\" is derived from the title of his painting Impression, soleil levant (Impression, Sunrise), which was exhibited in 1874 in the first of the independent exhibitions mounted by Monet and his associates as an alternative to the Salon de Paris.\n\tMonet\'s ambition of documenting the French countryside led him to adopt a method of painting the same scene many times in order to capture the changing of light and the passing of the seasons. From 1883 Monet lived in Giverny, where he purchased a house and property, and began a vast landscaping project which included lily ponds that would become the subjects of his best-known works. In 1899 he began painting the water lilies, first in vertical views with a Japanese bridge as a central feature, and later in the series of large-scale paintings that was to occupy him continuously for the next 20 years of his life.\n\tMonet has been described as \"the driving force behind Impressionism\". Crucial to the art of the Impressionist painters was the understanding of the effects of light on the local colour of objects, and the effects of the juxtaposition of colours with each other. Monet\'s long career as a painter was spent in the pursuit of this aim.\n\tIn 1856, his chance meeting with Eugene Boudin, a painter of small beach scenes, opened his eyes to the possibility of plein-air painting. From that time, with a short interruption for military service, he dedicated himself to searching for new and improved methods of painterly expression. To this end, as a young man, he visited the Paris Salon and familiarised himself with the works of older painters, and made friends with other young artists.\n\t His first series exhibited as such was of Haystacks, painted from different points of view and at different times of the day. Fifteen of the paintings were exhibited at the Galerie Durand-Ruel in 1891. In 1892 he produced what is probably his best-known series, twenty-six views of Rouen Cathedral. In these paintings Monet broke with painterly traditions by cropping the subject so that only a portion of the facade is seen on the canvas. The paintings do not focus on the grand Medieval building, but on the play of light and shade across its surface, transforming the solid masonry. To this day critics praise him with comments such as this one: \"Monet, with a scientific precision, has given us an unparalleled and unexcelled record of the passing of time as seen in the movement of light over identical forms.\"</string>
    <string name="title_2_3">Oscar-Claude Monet</string>

    <string name="theory_2_1">Haystacks is a title of a series of impressionist paintings by Claude Monet. The primary subjects of all of the paintings in the series are stacks of hay in the field after the harvest season. The title refers primarily to a twenty-five canvas series begun in the end of summer of 1890 and continued through the following spring, using that year\'s harvest. Some use a broader definition of the title to refer to other paintings by Monet with this same theme. The series is known for its thematic use of repetition to show differences in perception of light across various times of day, seasons, and types of weather. The subjects were painted in fields near Monet\'s home in Giverny, France.\n\tMonet noticed this subject on a casual walk. He requested that his stepdaughter Blanche Hoschedé bring him two canvases. He believed that one canvas for overcast weather and one for sunny weather would be sufficient. However, he realized he could not demonstrate the several distinct impressions on one or two canvases. As a result, his willing helper was quickly carting as many canvases as a wheelbarrow could hold. His daily routine involved carting paints, easels, and many unfinished canvases and working on whichever canvas most closely resembled the scene of the moment as conditions fluctuated. Although he began painting realistic depictions en plein air, he eventually revised initial effects in a studio to both generate contrast and preserve the harmony within the series.\n\tAlthough the mundane subject was constant throughout this series, the underlying theme may be seen as the transience of light. This concept enabled him to use repetition to show nuances of perception as seasons, time of day, and weather changes. The constant subject provided the basis from which comparisons could be made in changes of light across this nuanced series. The first paintings in the series were started in late September or early October 1890, and he continued producing these paintings for about seven months. These paintings made Monet the first painter to paint such a large quantity of pictures of the same subject matter differentiated by light, weather, atmosphere and perspective\n\tThis series is one of Monet\'s earliest that relied on thematic repetition to illustrate nuances in perception across natural variation such as times of day, seasons, and types of weather.</string>
    <string name="title_2_1">Haystacks</string>

    <string name="theory_2_2">Water Lilies  is a series of approximately 250 oil paintings by French Impressionist Claude Monet. The paintings depict Monet\'s flower garden at Giverny and were the main focus of Monet\'s artistic production during the last thirty years of his life. Many of the works were painted while Monet suffered from cataracts.\n\tMonet\'s career long serial motif of producing and exhibiting a series of paintings related by subject and perspective began in 1889, with at least ten paintings done at the Valley of the Creuse, which were shown at the Galerie Georges Petit.\n\tDuring the 1920s, the state of France built a pair of oval rooms at the Musée de l\'Orangerie as a permanent home for eight water lily murals by Monet. The exhibit opened to the public on 16 May 1927, a few months after Monet\'s death.[1] Sixty water lily paintings from around the world were assembled for a special exhibition at the Musée de l\'Orangerie in 1999.\n\tOn 19 June 2007, one of Monet\'s water lily paintings sold for £18.5 million at a Sotheby\'s auction in London. On 24 June 2008 another of Monet\'s water lily paintings, Le bassin aux nymphéas, sold for almost £41 million at Christie\'s in London, almost double the estimate of £18 to £24 million. Those prices just show how his painting are admired even today</string>
    <string name="title_2_2">Water Lilies</string>

    <string name="theory_2_6">Pierre-Auguste Renoir, commonly known as Auguste Renoir (25 February 1841 – 3 December 1919), was a French artist who was a leading painter in the development of the Impressionist style. As a celebrator of beauty, and especially feminine sensuality, it has been said that \"Renoir is the final representative of a tradition which runs directly from Rubens to Watteau.\"\n\tRenoir\'s paintings are notable for their vibrant light and saturated color, most often focusing on people in intimate and candid compositions. The female nude was one of his primary subjects. In characteristic Impressionist style, Renoir suggested the details of a scene through freely brushed touches of color, so that his figures softly fuse with one another and their surroundings.\n\tOne of the best known Impressionist works is Renoir\'s 1876 Dance at Le Moulin de la Galette (Bal du moulin de la Galette). The painting depicts an open-air scene, crowded with people at a popular dance garden on the Butte Montmartre close to where he lived. The works of his early maturity were typically Impressionist snapshots of real life, full of sparkling color and light. By the mid-1880s, however, he had broken with the movement to apply a more disciplined formal technique to portraits and figure paintings, particularly of women. It was a trip to Italy in 1881, when he saw works by Raphael and other Renaissance masters, that convinced him that he was on the wrong path, and for the next several years he painted in a more severe style in an attempt to return to classicism. Concentrating on his drawing and emphasizing the outlines of figures, he painted works such as The Large Bathers  during what is sometimes called his \"Ingres period\".\n\tAfter 1890 he changed direction again. To dissolve outlines, as in his earlier work, he returned to thinly brushed color. From this period onward he concentrated on monumental nudes and domestic scenes, fine examples of which are Girls at the Piano, 1892, and Grandes Baigneuses, 1887. The latter painting is the most typical and successful of Renoir\'s late, abundantly fleshed nudes.\n\tA prolific artist, he created several thousand paintings. The warm sensuality of Renoir\'s style made his paintings some of the most well-known and frequently reproduced works in the history of art. The single largest collection of his works—181 paintings in all—is at the Barnes Foundation, in Philadelphia.</string>
    <string name="title_2_6">Pierre-Auguste Renoir</string>

    <string name="theory_2_4">Bal du moulin de la Galette is an 1876 painting by French artist Pierre-Auguste Renoir. It is housed at the Musée d\'Orsay in Paris and is one of Impressionism\'s most celebrated masterpieces. The painting depicts a typical Sunday afternoon at Moulin de la Galette in the district of Montmartre in Paris. In the late 19th century, working class Parisians would dress up and spend time there dancing, drinking, and eating galettes into the evening.\n\tLike other works of Renoir\'s early maturity, Bal du moulin de la Galette is a typically Impressionist snapshot of real life. It shows a richness of form, a fluidity of brush stroke, and a flickering light.\n\tRenoir conceived his project of painting the dancing at Le Moulin de la Galette in May 1876 and its execution is described in full by his civil servant friend Georges Rivière in his memoir Renoir et ses amis.\n\tRenoir painted a smaller version of the picture with the same title. Apart from their size, the two paintings are virtually identical, although the smaller is painted in a more fluid manner than the d\'Orsay version. One is presumably a copy of the original, but it is not known which is the original. It is not even known which was the one first exhibited at the 3rd Impressionist exhibition of 1877, because although the painting was catalogued and given favourable attention by critics, its entry did not indicate the size of the painting, information that would serve to identify it.\n\tAt the time of sale, it was one of the top two most expensive artworks ever sold, together with van Gogh\'s Portrait of Dr. Gachet.</string>
    <string name="title_2_4">Bal</string>

    <string name="theory_2_5">Luncheon of the Boating Party is a painting by French impressionist Pierre-Auguste Renoir. Included in the Seventh Impressionist Exhibition in 1882, it was identified as the best painting in the show by three critics.\n\tThe painting, combining figures, still-life, and landscape in one work, depicts a group of Renoir\'s friends relaxing on a balcony at the Maison Fournaise along the Seine river in Chatou, France. The painter and art patron, Gustave Caillebotte, is seated in the lower right. Renoir\'s future wife, Aline Charigot, is in the foreground playing with a small dog. On the table is fruit and wine.\n\tThe diagonal of the railing serves to demarcate the two halves of the composition, one densely packed with figures, the other all but empty, save for the two figures of the proprietor\'s daughter Louise-Alphonsine Fournaise and her brother, Alphonse Fournaise, Jr, which are made prominent by this contrast. In this painting Renoir has captured a great deal of light. The main focus of light is coming from the large opening in the balcony, beside the large singleted man in the hat. The singlets of both men in the foreground and the table-cloth all work together to reflect this light and send it through the whole composition.\n\tAt the Seventh Impressionist Exhibition in 1882, the painting generally received praise from critics, such as \"It is fresh and free without being too bawdy,\" , \"…one of the best things Renoir has painted… . There are bits of drawing that are completely remarkable, drawing- true drawing- that is a result of the juxtaposition of hues and not of line. It is one of the most beautiful pieces that this insurrectionist art by Independent artists has produced.\" or  \"If he had learned to draw, Renoir would have a very pretty picture…\"</string>
    <string name="title_2_5">Boating Party</string>

    <string name="theory_2_8">Edgar Degas (19 July 1834 – 27 September 1917) was a French artist famous for his paintings, sculptures, prints, and drawings. He is especially identified with the subject of dance; more than half of his works depict dancers. He is regarded as one of the founders of Impressionism, although he rejected the term, preferring to be called a realist. He was a superb draftsman, and particularly masterly in depicting movement, as can be seen in his renditions of dancers, racecourse subjects and female nudes. His portraits are notable for their psychological complexity and for their portrayal of human isolation.\n\tAt the beginning of his career, he wanted to be a history painter, a calling for which he was well prepared by his rigorous academic training and close study of classic art. In his early thirties, he changed course, and by bringing the traditional methods of a history painter to bear on contemporary subject matter, he became a classical painter of modern life.\n\tDegas is often identified as an Impressionist, an understandable but insufficient description. Impressionism originated in the 1860s and 1870s and grew, in part, from the realism of such painters as Courbet and Corot. The Impressionists painted the realities of the world around them using bright, \"dazzling\" colors, concentrating primarily on the effects of light, and hoping to infuse their scenes with immediacy. They wanted to express what they saw in that exact moment.\n\tTechnically, Degas differs from the Impressionists in that he \"never adopted the Impressionist color fleck\", and he continually belittled their practice of painting en plein air.He was often as anti-impressionist as the critics who reviewed the shows. As Degas himself explained, \"no art was ever less spontaneous than mine. What I do is the result of reflection and of the study of the great masters; of inspiration, spontaneity, temperament, I know nothing.\" Nonetheless, he is described more accurately as an Impressionist than as a member of any other movement.\n\tDuring his life, public reception of Degas\'s work ranged from admiration to contempt. As a promising artist in the conventional mode, Degas had a number of paintings accepted in the Salon between 1865 and 1870. These works received praise from Pierre Puvis de Chavannes and the critic Jules-Antoine Castagnary. He soon changed his mind and joined forces with the Impressionists, however, and rejected the rigid rules, judgements, and elitism of the Salon—just as the Salon and general public initially rejected the experimentalism of the Impressionists.</string>
    <string name="title_2_8">Edgar Degas</string>

    <string name="theory_2_7">The Bellelli Family, also known as Family Portrait, is an oil painting on canvas by Edgar Degas, painted ca. 1858–1867, and housed in the Musée d\'Orsay. A masterwork of Degas\' youth, the painting is a portrait of his aunt, her husband, and their two young daughters.\n\tWhile finishing his artistic training in Italy, Degas drew and painted his aunt Laura, her husband the baron Gennaro Bellelli , and their daughters Giulia and Giovanna. Although it is not known for certain when or where Degas executed the painting, it is believed that he utilized studies done in Italy to complete the work after his return to Paris. Laura, his father\'s sister, is depicted in a dress which symbolizes mourning for her father, who had recently died and appears in the framed portrait behind her. Laura Bellelli\'s countenance is dignified and austere, her gesture connected with those of her daughters. Her husband, by contrast, appears to be separated from his family. His association with business and the outside world is implied by his position at his desk. Giulia holds a livelier pose than that of her sister Giovanna, whose restraint appears to underscore the familial tensions.\n\tViewed alongside the work of Degas\' contemporaries, the painting\'s uniqueness was due in large part to the composition, which presents a family portrait painted on the grand scale of a historical drama, and whose content has been interpreted as psychologically penetrating, with the placement of the figures suggestive of the parents\' alienation from one another, and of the divided loyalties of their children.\n\tWhen exhibited at the sale of Degas\' atelier in 1918, the picture elicited some confusion from critics; one called it \"as dull as a Flemish interior, although the dry technique is distinctive.\" Most of the reviews were positive, and with the country at war, The Bellelli Family was seen as possessing a distinctly French character, a \"modern primitive\" that bore comparison to the Avignon Pieta. Since then, biographers of Degas have acknowledged it as the masterpiece of his youth.</string>
    <string name="title_2_7">The Bellielli Family</string>

    <string name="theory_2_11">Vincent Willem van Gogh (30 March 1853 – 29 July 1890) was a major Post-Impressionist painter. He was a Dutch artist whose work had a far-reaching influence on 20th-century art. His output includes portraits, self portraits, landscapes and still lifes of cypresses, wheat fields and sunflowers. Van Gogh drew as a child but did not paint until his late twenties; he completed many of his best-known works during the last two years of his life. In just over a decade he produced more than 2,100 artworks, including 860 oil paintings and more than 1,300 watercolors, drawings, sketches and prints.\n\tVan Gogh drew and painted with watercolors while at school—only a few of these paintings survive and authorship is challenged on some of those that do. When he committed to art as an adult, he began at an elementary level, copying the Cours de dessin, a drawing course edited by Charles Bargue. Within two years he had begun to seek commissions. In spring 1882, his uncle, Cornelis Marinus, owner of a well-known gallery of contemporary art in Amsterdam, asked him for drawings of the Hague. Van Gogh\'s work did not live up to his uncle\'s expectations. Marinus offered a second commission, this time specifying the subject matter in detail, but was once again disappointed with the result. Nevertheless, Van Gogh persevered. He improved the lighting of his studio by installing variable shutters and experimented with a variety of drawing materials. For more than a year he worked on single figures – highly elaborated studies in \"Black and White\", which at the time gained him only criticism. Today, they are recognized as his first masterpieces.\n\tAfter becoming familiar with Impressionist and Neo-Impressionist techniques and theories, Van Gogh went to Arles to develop on these new possibilities. But within a short time, older ideas on art and work reappeared: ideas such as working with serial imagery on related or contrasting subject matter, which would reflect on the purposes of art. As his work progressed, he painted many Self-portraits. Already in 1884 in Nuenen he had worked on a series that was to decorate the dining room of a friend in Eindhoven. Similarly in Arles, in spring 1888 he arranged his Flowering Orchards into triptychs, began a series of figures that found its end in The Roulin Family series, and finally, when Gauguin had consented to work and live in Arles side-by-side with Van Gogh, he started to work on The Décorations for the Yellow House, which was by some accounts the most ambitious effort he ever undertook. Most of his later work is involved with elaborating on or revising its fundamental settings. In the spring of 1889, he painted another, smaller group of orchards. In an April letter to Theo, he said, \"I have 6 studies of Spring, two of them large orchards. There is little time because these effects are so short-lived.\"\n\tArt historian Albert Boime believes that Van Gogh – even in seemingly fantastical compositions like Starry Night – based his work in reality. The White House at Night, shows a house at twilight with a prominent star surrounded by a yellow halo in the sky. Astronomers at Southwest Texas State University in San Marcos calculated that the star is Venus, which was bright in the evening sky in June 1890 when Van Gogh is believed to have painted the picture.</string>
    <string name="title_2_11">Vincent van Gogh</string>

    <string name="theory_2_9">The Starry Night is an oil on canvas by the Dutch post-impressionist painter Vincent van Gogh. Painted in June, 1889, it depicts the view from the east-facing window of his asylum room at Saint-Rémy-de-Provence, just before sunrise, with the addition of an idealized village.  It is regarded as among Van Gogh\'s finest works, and one of the most recognized monuments in the history of Western culture.\n\tAlthough The Starry Night was painted during the day in Van Gogh\'s ground-floor studio, it would be inaccurate to state that the picture was painted from memory. The view has been identified as the one from his bedroom window, facing east, a view which Van Gogh painted variations of no fewer than twenty-one times, including The Starry Night.\n\tVan Gogh depicted the view at different times of day and under various weather conditions, including sunrise, moonrise, sunshine-filled days, overcast days, windy days, and one day with rain. The hospital staff did not allow Van Gogh to paint in his bedroom, but he was able to make sketches in ink or charcoal on paper, and eventually he would base newer variations on previous versions. The pictorial element uniting all of these paintings is the diagonal line coming in from the right depicting the low rolling hills of the Alpilles mountains.\n\tOne of the first paintings of the view was Mountainous Landscape Behind Saint-Rémy, now in Copenhagen, which Van Gogh identified in a letter to his sister Wil from 16 June 1889 as hanging in his studio to dry. Two days later, he wrote to his brother that he had painted \"a starry sky.\" The Starry Night is the only nocturne painting in the series of views from his bedroom window. In early June Vincent wrote to Theo, \"This morning I saw the countryside from my window a long time before sunrise with nothing but the morning star, which looked very big.\" Two scholars working independently of each other have determined that Venus was indeed visible in Provence in the spring of 1889. So the brightest \"star\" in the painting, just to the viewer\'s right of the cypress tree, is actually Venus.\n\tThe moon is stylized, as astronomical records indicate that the moon was waning gibbous at the time Van Gogh painted the picture.Even if the phase of the moon had been a waning crescent at the time, Van Gogh\'s moon is not astronomically correct.The one pictorial element that was definitely not visible from Van Gogh\'s cell is the village, which is based on a sketch made from a hillside above the village of Saint-Rémy.\n\t Needless to say the painting is extremely popular even today with it being included in movies and tv shows.</string>
    <string name="title_2_9">The Starry Night</string>

    <string name="theory_2_10">Portrait of Dr. Gachet is one of the most revered paintings by the Dutch artist Vincent van Gogh. It depicts Dr. Paul Gachet who took care of Van Gogh during the final months of his life. There are two authenticated versions of the portrait, both painted in June 1890 at Auvers-sur-Oise. Both show Gachet sitting at a table and leaning his head on his right arm but they are easily differentiated in color and style. In 1990, the first version fetched a record price of $82.5 million.\n\tVan Gogh painted Gachet resting his right elbow on a red table, head in hand. Two yellow books as well as the purple medicinal herb foxglove are displayed on the table. The foxglove in the painting is a plant from which digitalis is extracted for the treatment of certain heart complaints, perhaps an attribute of Gachet as a physician.The doctor\'s \"sensitive face\", which Van Gogh wrote to Paul Gauguin carried \"the heartbroken expression of our time\".\n\tWith the Portrait of Dr. Gachet, Van Gogh sought to create a \"modern portrait\", which he wrote to his sister \"impassions me most—much, much more than all the rest of my métier.\"He also wrote, \"My self-portrait is done in nearly the same way but the blue is the fine blue of the Midi, and the clothes are a light lilac,\".</string>
    <string name="title_2_10">Dr. Gachet</string>

    <string name="theory_3_0">Expressionism was a modernist movement, initially in poetry and painting, originating in Germany at the beginning of the 20th century. Its typical trait is to present the world solely from a subjective perspective, distorting it radically for emotional effect in order to evoke moods or ideas. Expressionist artists sought to express meaning or emotional experience rather than physical reality.\n\tExpressionism was developed as an avant-garde style before the First World War. The term is sometimes suggestive of angst. The Expressionist emphasis on individual perspective has been characterized as a reaction to positivism and other artistic styles such as Naturalism and Impressionism. \n\tWhile the word expressionist was used in the modern sense as early as 1850, its origin is sometimes traced to paintings exhibited in 1901 in Paris by an obscure artist Julien–Auguste Hervé, which he called Expressionismes. Though an alternate view is that the term was coined by the Czech art historian Antonin Matějček in 1910, as the opposite of impressionism: \"An Expressionist wishes, above all, to express himself… (an Expressionist rejects) immediate perception and builds on more complex psychic structures… Impressions and mental images that pass through mental peoples soul as through a filter which rids them of all substantial accretions to produce their clear essence […and] are assimilated and condense into more general forms, into types, which he transcribes through simple short-hand formulae and symbols.\"</string>
    <string name="title_3_0">Expressionism</string>

    <string name="theory_3_4">Edvard Munch (12 December 1863 – 23 January 1944) was a Norwegian painter and printmaker whose intensely evocative treatment of psychological themes built upon some of the main tenets of late 19th-century Symbolism and greatly influenced German Expressionism in the early 20th century. One of his most well-known works is The Scream of 1893.\n\tIn 1885, Edvard Munch traveled to Paris, and was extremely influenced by impressionism artists Claude Monet, Edouard Manet, and followed by the post-impressionism artists Van Gogh, Paul Cezanne, and Gauguin. In fact, the main style of Munch\'s work is post-impressionism, and focused on this style.\n\t„Nature is not only all that is visible to the eye… it also includes the inner pictures of the soul.”\n\tMuch of the work which Edvard Munch created, was referred to as the style known as symbolism. This is mainly because of the fact that the pieces which he created, and the paintings he made, focused on the internal view of the objects, as opposed to the exterior, and what the eye could see. He would design many of his pieces around the way he felt, or the emotions he was repressing, which caused his work to showcase inward feeling, and more of a personal sense of art, as opposed to the external view, and the way everyone else would see the piece which he was portraying in any piece that he was designing.</string>
    <string name="title_3_4">Edvard Munch</string>

    <string name="theory_3_1">The Scream (Norwegian: Skrik) is the popular name given to each of four versions of a composition, created as both paintings and pastels, by the Expressionist artist Edvard Munch between 1893 and 1910. Der Schrei der Natur (The Scream of Nature) is the title Munch gave to these works, all of which show a figure with an agonized expression against a landscape with a tumultuous orange sky. Arthur Lubow has described The Scream as \"an icon of modern art, a Mona Lisa for our time.\"\n\tEdvard Munch created the four versions in various media. The fourth version (pastel, 1895) was sold for $119,922,600 at Sotheby\'s Impressionist and Modern Art auction on 2 May 2012 to financier Leon Black, the second highest nominal price paid for a painting at auction. The Scream has been the target of several high-profile art thefts. In 1994, the version in the National Gallery was stolen. It was recovered several months later. In 2004, both The Scream and Madonna were stolen from the Munch Museum, and were both recovered two years later.\n\tIn his diary in an entry headed, Nice 22 January 1892, Munch described his inspiration for the image:\n\t„One evening I was walking along a path, the city was on one side and the fjord below. I felt tired and ill. I stopped and looked out over the fjord—the sun was setting, and the clouds turning blood red. I sensed a scream passing through nature; it seemed to me that I heard the scream. I painted this picture, painted the clouds as actual blood. The color shrieked. This became The Scream.“</string>
    <string name="title_3_1">The Scream</string>

    <string name="theory_3_2">When Jens Thiis bought this picture for the National Gallery, Oslo, in 1909 the public was shocked; one critic denounced it as portraying a drunken prostitute. This is unlikely to have been Munch\'s idea. He did paint several pictures of prostitutes, tending to depict them as unattractive or even grotesque, whereas this woman closely resembles the Madonna and, different though the setting, shares her ethereal beauty. She is probably intended to illustrate one aspect of the essence of protean womanhood portrayed in that work. Both paintings in fact relate to a lost picture by Munch that Hans Jaeger had with him in his prison cell when jailed in 1886 for publishing From Christiania\'s Bohemia, a novel in which descriptions of free bohemian life parallel what is shown here. The present picture is more directly a replica, modified by his style of the 1890s, of the same subject painted in 1885–86 and also lost. One important Norwegian precedent for the depiction of a dissolute woman would undoubtedly have been known to Munch, Hans Heyerdahl\'s tiny, exquisite painting of The Champagne Girl, which was also strongly attacked when exhibited. If Munch\'s picture represents The Day After, Heyerdahl\'s might be called \'The Evening Before.\'</string>
    <string name="title_3_2">The day after</string>

    <string name="theory_3_3">Originally called Loving Woman, this picture can be taken to symbolize what Munch considered the essential acts of the female life cycle: sexual intercourse, causing fertilization, procreation and death. Evidence for the first is in the picture itself, an intensified, spiritualized variation in the nude of the \'mating\' pose, the woman depicted as though recumbent beneath her lover. The ethereal beauty of her face was said to resemble both Dagny Przybyszewska and her sister Ragnhild Backstrom. Procreation was implied by the decoration of the original frame, later discarded, on which were painted drops of semen and an embryo. That Munch associated the image with death is clear from his own comments on the picture, in which he sees it as representing the eternal cyclical process of generation and decay in nature. He continually connected love with death: for the man, because it eviscerated him, for the woman, because, following Schopenhauer, he appears to have thought her function ended with child-bearing.</string>
    <string name="title_3_3">Maddona</string>

    <string name="theory_3_7">Francis Bacon (28 October 1909 – 28 April 1992) was an Anglo-Irish figurative painter known for his bold, emotionally charged and raw imagery. His painterly abstracted figures are typically isolated in glass or steel geometrical cages, set against flat, nondescript backgrounds. Bacon took up painting in his early 20s but worked sporadically and uncertainly until his mid-30s. Unsure of his ability, he drifted as a highly complex bon vivant, homosexual, gambler and interior decorator and designer of furniture, rugs and bathroom tiles. He later admitted that his artistic career was delayed because he spent too long looking for subject matter that could sustain his interest. His breakthrough came with the 1944 triptych Three Studies for Figures at the Base of a Crucifixion, which in the immediate aftermath of the Second World War, sealed his reputation as a uniquely bleak chronicler of the human condition. Remarking on the cultural significance of Three Studies, John Russell observed that \"there was painting in England before the Three Studies, and painting after them, and no one…can confuse the two.\"\n\tBacon was equally reviled and acclaimed during his lifetime. Margaret Thatcher described him as \"that man who paints those dreadful pictures\", but he was the subject of two Tate retrospectives and a major showing in 1971 at the Grand Palais. Since his death his reputation and market value have grown steadily, and his work is amongst the most acclaimed, expensive and sought-after. In the late 1990s a number of major works, previously assumed destroyed, including early 1950s popes and 1960s portraits, reemerged to set record prices at auction. On 12 November 2013 his Three Studies of Lucian Freud set the world record as the most expensive piece of art sold at auction, selling for $142,405,000, until exceeded by the sale of a Picasso in May 2015.</string>
    <string name="title_3_7">Francis Bacon</string>

    <string name="theory_3_5">Study after Velázquez\'s Portrait of Pope Innocent X is a 1953 painting by the artist Francis Bacon. The work shows a distorted version of the Portrait of Innocent X painted by Spanish artist Diego Velázquez in 1650. The work is one of a series of over 45 variants of the Velázquez painting which Bacon executed throughout the 1950s and early 1960s. The picture was described by Gilles Deleuze as an example of creative re-interpretation of the classical\n\tWhen asked why he was compelled to revisit the subject so often, Bacon replied that he had nothing against the Popes, that he merely sought \"an excuse to use these colours, and you can\'t give ordinary clothes that purple colour without getting into a sort of false fauve manner.\"\n\tIn Bacon\'s version of Velázquez\'s masterpiece, the Pope is shown screaming yet his voice is \"silenced\" by the enclosing drapes and dark rich colors. The dark colors of the background lend a grotesque and nightmarish tone to the painting. The pleated curtains of the backdrop are rendered transparent and appear to fall through the representation of the Pope\'s face.</string>
    <string name="title_3_5">Portrait of Pope Innocent X</string>

    <string name="theory_3_6">Three Studies for Figures at the Base of a Crucifixion is a 1944 triptych painted by the Irish-born British artist Francis Bacon. The work is based on the Eumenides—or Furies—of Aeschylus\'s The Oresteia, and depicts three writhing anthropomorphic creatures set against a flat burnt orange background. Three Studies was executed in oil paint and pastel on Sundeala fibre board and completed within two weeks.\n\tThe triptych summarises themes explored in Bacon\'s previous paintings, including his examination of Picasso\'s biomorphs and his interpretations of the Crucifixion and the Greek Furies. Bacon did not realise his original intention to paint a large crucifixion scene and place the figures at the foot of the cross.\n\The Three Studies triptych is generally considered Bacon\'s first mature piece; he regarded his works before the triptych as irrelevant, and throughout his life tried to suppress their appearance on the art market. When the painting was first exhibited in 1945 it caused a sensation and helped to establish him as one of the foremost post-war painters. Remarking on the cultural significance of Three Studies, the critic John Russell observed in 1971 that \"there was painting in England before the Three Studies, and painting after them, and no one … can confuse the two.\"</string>
    <string name="title_3_6">Three Studies for Figures</string>

    <string name="theory_3_10">Franz Marc (February 8, 1880 – March 4, 1916) was a German painter and printmaker, one of the key figures of the German Expressionist movement. He was a founding member of Der Blaue Reiter (The Blue Rider), a journal whose name later became synonymous with the circle of artists collaborating in it.\n\tMarc made some sixty prints in woodcut and lithography. Most of his mature work portrays animals, usually in natural settings. His work is characterized by bright primary color, an almost cubist portrayal of animals, stark simplicity and a profound sense of emotion. Even in his own time, his work attracted notice in influential circles. Marc gave an emotional meaning or purpose to the colors he used in his work: blue was used to portray masculinity and spirituality, yellow represented feminine joy, and red encased the sound of violence.</string>
    <string name="title_3_10">Franz Marc</string>

    <string name="theory_3_8">Fate of the Animals is a painting by Franz Marc created in 1913. It is oil on canvas. This work contrasts most of Marc\'s other works by presenting animals in a brutal way rather than depicting them in a peaceful manner. Marc\'s strong ties with animals as his subjects remains uncertain, but it is predicted to stem from his childhood dog. Fate of the Animals remains one of Marc\'s most famous pieces and displays Der Blaue Reiter style that he co-founded with Wassily Kandinsky. The painting currently resides in the Kunstmuseum in Basel, Switzerland.\n\tThis work is also characteristic of the sense of apocalypse and doom which began to taint Marc\'s work at this time and could be related to his feelings on the impending war. In a 1915 letter to his wife Maria, Marc explains that this change in his art occurred because he began to see the ugliness in animals which he had previously thought only existed in humans. He states that he was no longer able to see the beauty which animals had once represented for him. The animal motifs which once conveyed a sense of emotion no longer held their appeal and possibility. The application of paint and the division of the picture plane through the use of lines and geometric shapes now carried the emotional charge previously conveyed by animals. This change may be related to Marc\'s ideas on the impending war. In apprehension of the First World War, Marc was part of the school of thought that the war would purify and redeem the universe of all that was bad. Marc no longer saw animals as separate entities in their own perfect kingdom, as he had once represented them. At the point when Marc began to identify the ugliness in animals, he recognized them as part of the universe which man also inhabited and which was in need of redemption.</string>
    <string name="title_3_8">Fate of the Animals</string>

    <string name="theory_3_9">Marc wrote: \"Every color must say clearly \'who and what it is, and must, moreover, be related to a clear form.\"\n\nIn Red Horses, the depiction is sufficiently simplified so as to allow the color to be paramount. The dynamic red of the horses suggested that Marc intended to emphasize an earthly orientation for this particular group of animals. The white area surmounting the pyramidally arranged horses can be understood as symbolizing purity or solace in comparison to the rest of the canvas. To interpret Marc\'s use of green in the upper third of the painting with regard to his thoughts on color is also enlightening. He said that once green in introduced, \"You never entirely bring the eternally material, brutal red to rest.\" In that spirit, the horses seem nervous beyond all possibility of resolution. Only the blue, as Marc prescribed, lends a peaceful note to the agitated atmosphere.</string>
    <string name="title_3_9">Red Horses</string>

    <string name="theory_3_13">Paul Klee (18 December 1879 – 29 June 1940) was a Swiss-German painter. His highly individual style was influenced by movements in art that included expressionism, cubism, and surrealism. Klee was a natural draftsman who experimented with and eventually deeply explored color theory, writing about it extensively; his lectures Writings on Form and Design Theory (Schriften zur Form und Gestaltungslehre), published in English as the Paul Klee Notebooks, are held to be as important for modern art as Leonardo da Vinci\'s A Treatise on Painting for the Renaissance. He and his colleague, Russian painter Wassily Kandinsky, both taught at the Bauhaus school of art, design and architecture. His works reflect his dry humor and his sometimes childlike perspective, his personal moods and beliefs, and his musicality.\n\tKlee has been variously associated with Expressionism, Cubism, Futurism, Surrealism, and Abstraction, but his pictures are difficult to classify. He generally worked in isolation from his peers, and interpreted new art trends in his own way. He was inventive in his methods and technique. Klee worked in many different media—oil paint, watercolor, ink, pastel, etching, and others. He often combined them into one work. He used canvas, burlap, muslin, linen, gauze, cardboard, metal foils, fabric, wallpaper, and newsprint. Klee employed spray paint, knife application, stamping, glazing, and impasto, and mixed media such as oil with watercolor, watercolor with pen and India ink, and oil with tempera.</string>
    <string name="title_3_13">Paul Klee</string>

    <string name="theory_3_11">Twittering Machine (Die Zwitscher-Maschine) is a 1922 watercolor and pen and ink oil transfer on paper by Swiss-German painter Paul Klee. Like other artworks by Klee, it blends biology and machinery, depicting a loosely sketched group of birds on a wire or branch connected to a hand-crank. Interpretations of the work vary widely: it has been perceived as a nightmarish lure for the viewer or a depiction of the helplessness of the artist, but also as a triumph of nature over mechanical pursuits. It has been seen as a visual representation of the mechanics of sound.\n\tThe picture depicts a group of birds, largely line drawings; all save the first are shackled on a wire (or, according to The Washington Post, a \"sine-wave branch\") over a blue and purple background which the MoMA equates with the \"misty cool blue of night giv[ing] way to the pink flow of dawn\". Each of the birds is open-beaked, with a jagged or rounded shape emerging from its mouth, widely interpreted as its protruding tongue. The end of the perch dips into a crank.\n\tThe bird with an exclamation point in its mouth represents the twitter\'s full volume; the one with an arrow in its beak symbolizes an accompanying shrillness – a horizontal thrust of piercing song. Since a characteristic of chirping birds is that their racket resumes as soon as it seems to be ending, the bird in the center droops with lolling tongue, while another begins to falter in song; both birds will come up again full blast as soon as the machine\'s crank is turned.</string>
    <string name="title_3_11">Twittering Machine</string>

    <string name="theory_3_12">Type: oil on canvas\n\nCompleted in 1922, Senecio is a manifestation of Paul’s sense of humor and African culture. The simple colors and shapes, Paul makes use of various shades of orange, red, and yellow to reveal portrait of an old man. Artistic use of shapes gives the false impression that one eye browse is raised. His left eye brow is represented by a triangle while the other one is made of a simple curved line. The portrait is also called Head of a Man Going Senile and intentionally mimics children’s artwork by using ambiguous shapes and forms with minimal facial details.</string>
    <string name="title_3_12">Senecio</string>

    <string name="theory_4_0">Cubism has been considered the most influential art movement of the 20th century. It was created by Pablo Picasso (Spanish, 1881–1973) and Georges Braque (French, 1882–1963) in Paris between 1907 and 1914. The movement was joined by Jean Metzinger, Albert Gleizes, Robert Delaunay, Henri Le Fauconnier and Juan Gris. That avant-garde visual art style revolutionized European painting and sculpture, and inspired related movements in music, literature and architecture.\n\tA primary influence that led to Cubism was the representation of three-dimensional form in the late works of Paul Cézanne. In Cubist artwork, objects are analyzed, broken up and reassembled in an abstracted form-instead of depicting objects from one viewpoint, the artist depicts the subject from a multitude of viewpoints to represent the subject in a greater context. Traditional subjects like nude figures, landscapes, and still lifes were reinvented as increasingly fragmented compositions made of geometrical components and often represented from several angles at once. The artists adopted a neutral palette of browns and blacks, intending the viewer to focus on the geometric composition rather than the color.\n\tOne of the most influential collective of painters and sculptors associated with Cubism was The Section d’Or, also known as Groupe de Puteaux, active from 1911 through about 1914. They made the most important pre-World War I Cubist exhibition The Salon de la Section d’Or at the Galerie La Boétie in Paris, October 1912; exposing Cubism to a wide audience. Undoubtedly, due to the great success of the exhibition, Cubism became recognized as a tendency, genre or style in art with a specific common philosophy or goal: a new avant-garde movement.\n\tAfter World War I, with the support given by the dealer Léonce Rosenberg, Cubism returned as a central issue for artists, and continued as such until the mid-1920s when its avant-garde status was rendered questionable by the emergence of geometric abstraction and Surrealism in Paris. Many Cubists, including Picasso, Braque, Gris, Léger, Gleizes, and Metzinger, while developing other styles, returned periodically to Cubism, even well after 1925. Cubism after 1918 can be seen as part of a wide ideological shift towards conservatism in both French society and culture.</string>
    <string name="title_4_0">Cubism</string>

    <string name="theory_4_6">Georges Braque (13 May 1882 – 31 August 1963) was a major 20th-century French painter, collagist, draughtsman, printmaker and sculptor. His most important contributions to the history of art were in his alliance with Fauvism from 1906, and the role he played in the development of Cubism. Braque’s work between 1908 and 1912 is closely associated with that of his colleague Pablo Picasso. Their respective Cubist works were indistinguishable for many years, yet the quiet nature of Braque was partially eclipsed by the fame and notoriety of Picasso.\n\tBraque\'s paintings of 1908–1913 reflected his new interest in geometry and simultaneous perspective. He conducted an intense study of the effects of light and perspective and the technical means that painters use to represent these effects, seeming to question the most standard of artistic conventions. In his village scenes, for example, Braque frequently reduced an architectural structure to a geometric form approximating a cube, yet rendered its shading so that it looked both flat and three-dimensional by fragmenting the image. He showed this in the painting Houses at l\'Estaque. Beginning in 1909, Braque began to work closely with Pablo Picasso who had been developing a similar proto-Cubist style of painting. At the time, Pablo Picasso was influenced by Gauguin, Cézanne, African masks and Iberian sculpture while Braque was interested mainly in developing Cézanne\'s ideas of multiple perspectives. A comparison of the works of Picasso and Braque during 1908 reveals that the effect of his encounter with Picasso was more to accelerate and intensify Braque’s exploration of Cézanne’s ideas, rather than to divert his thinking in any essential way. Braque’s essential subject is the ordinary objects he has known practically forever. Picasso celebrates animation, while Braque celebrates contemplation.\n\tBraque died on 31 August 1963 in Paris. He is buried in the cemetery of the Church of St. Valery in Varengeville-sur-Mer, Normandy whose windows he designed. Braque\'s work is in most major museums throughout the world.</string>
    <string name="title_4_6">Georges Braque</string>

    <string name="theory_4_5">This picture is listed by Isarlov among Braque\'s works of 1909, with a note that it was taken up again and finished in 1912. However it was exhibited in Prague in May 1913 with the date 1911, and it has a Galerie Kahnweiler label on the back inscribed with the title and date \'Fishes 1911\'. \n\tOrdinary objects – a bottle and fishes on a plate, laid on a table with a drawer – have been dramatically fragmented to form a grid-like structure of interpenetrating planes. The traditional domestic subject matter and sober colours in this work can be seen as a reaction against the luminous hues and free expression of Braque’s earlier fauvist paintings.\n\tThe table top and the bottle provide the main compositional accents, while the remainder of the surface is broken down in secondary vertical and horizontal sections. Through these planes the bodies of the fish, fragmented and dislocated, can be traced in a series of subsidiary diagonals. Only their heads remain immediately legible, and these provide the spectator with a starting point for the reconstruction of the subject.</string>
    <string name="title_4_5">Bottle and Fishes</string>

    <string name="theory_4_3">Houses at l\'Estaque (French: Maisons à l\'Estaque) is a 1908 oil painting by Georges Braque. It is considered either an important Proto-Cubist landscape or the first Cubist landscape. The painting prompted art critic Louis Vauxcelles to mock it as being composed of cubes which led to the name of the movement. It is a response to works by Paul Cézannewho also lived in L\'Estaque at times.\n\t In Houses at L\'Estaque all the sensuous elements of Braque\'s previous years have been banished; color has been reduced to a severe combination of browns, dull greens and grays…The curving rhythms have given way to a system of verticals and horizontals, broken only by the forty-five degree diagonals of roof-tops and trees. All details have been eliminated and the foliage of the trees reduced to a minimum to reveal the geometric severity of the houses. These are continued upwards almost to the top of the canvas so that the eye is allowed no escape beyond them. The picture plane is further emphasized by the complete lack of aerial perspective (the far houses are, if anything, darker and stronger in value than the foreground house), and by the fact that occasionally contours are broken and forms opened up into each other. There is no central vanishing point; indeed in many of the houses all the canons of traditional perspective are completely broken</string>
    <string name="title_4_3">Houses at l\'Estaque</string>

    <string name="theory_4_4">Violin and Candle stick is Georges Braque’s masterpiece. It was painted during the spring of 1910 in Paris. This piece is painted on canvas using oil paint and its size is 60.96 cm x 50.17 cm. It is painted in monochromatic style; which is using one color only but with many different tones of the color. It also has a still-life theme, which means objects in the painting are carefully arranged. Some of the objects like violin and candle and be seen clearly while it is hard to tell what the other objects are. The painting is now exhibited at the San Francisco Museum of Modern art. \n\tResulting from Georges Braque’s love for stability and form and his intention to experiment Analytic Cubism, Violin and Candlestick is a painting that cracks, broke, and compressed the known objects and reconstructs it in multiple point-perspectives on a small space. He expressed this art of fragmentation as \"a technique for getting closer to the object.\" He fits multiple surfaces on a flat canvas giving the viewers a three dimensional view on a two dimensional surface. This painting is decided to be viewed from different angles. He also blends the objects and the background by opening up the black-outlined objects and topping their boundaries by using earth-toned colors for the whole painting.\n\tThe focus point of this painting is at the center where the objects are placed and the colors are darker, drawing viewers’ attention. However, the violin is placed on the left side of the viewer to make the viewers look at the different parts of the painting.</string>
    <string name="title_4_4">Violin and Candle</string>

    <string name="theory_4_9">Pablo Ruiz y Picasso, also known as Pablo Picasso (25 October 1881 – 8 April 1973), was a Spanish painter, sculptor, printmaker, ceramicist, stage designer, poet and playwright who spent most of his adult life in France. As one of the greatest and most influential artists of the 20th century, he is known for co-founding the Cubist movement, the invention of constructed sculpture, the co-invention of collage, and for the wide variety of styles that he helped develop and explore. He is regarded as the artist who most defined the revolutionary developments in the plastic arts in the opening decades of the 20th century. Among his most famous works are the proto-Cubist Les Demoiselles d\'Avignon(1907), and Guernica(1937), a portrayal of the Bombing of Guernica by the German and Italian airforces at the behest of the Spanish nationalist government during the Spanish Civil War.\n\tPicasso demonstrated extraordinary artistic talent in his early years, painting in a naturalistic manner through his childhood and adolescence. During the first decade of the 20th century, his style changed as he experimented with different theories, techniques, and ideas. His work is often categorised into periods. While the names of many of his later periods are debated, the most commonly accepted periods in his work are the Blue Period (1901–1904), the Rose Period (1904–1906), the African-influenced Period (1907–1909), Analytic Cubism (1909–1912), and Synthetic Cubism (1912–1919).\n\tIdeas developed during the African-influenced Period lead directly into the Cubist period that follows.  Analytic cubism (1909–1912) is a style of painting Picasso developed with Georges Braque using monochrome brownish and neutral colours. Both artists took apart objects and \"analyzed\" them in terms of their shapes. Picasso and Braque\'s paintings at this time share many similarities. Synthetic cubism (1912–1919) was a further development of the genre, in which cut paper fragments – often wallpaper or portions of newspaper pages – were pasted into compositions, marking the first use of collage in fine art.</string>
    <string name="title_4_9">Pablo Picasso</string>

    <string name="theory_4_8">Guernica is a mural-sized oil painting on canvas by Spanish artist Pablo Picasso completed by June 1937. The painting, which uses a palette of gray, black, and white, is known as one of the most moving and powerful anti-war paintings in history. Standing at 11 feet tall and 25.6 feet wide, the large mural shows the suffering of people, animals, and buildings wrenched by violence and chaos.\n\tThe painting is believed to be a response to the bombing of Guernica, a Basque Country villagein northern Spain, by German and Italian warplanes at the request of the Spanish Nationalists. Upon completion, Guernica was displayed around the world in a brief tour, becoming famous and widely acclaimed, and believed to have helped bring worldwide attention to the Spanish Civil War.\n\tThe overall scene is within a room where, at an open end on the left, a wide-eyed bull stands over a woman grieving over a dead child in her arms. The center is occupied by a horse falling in agony as it had just been run through by a spear or javelin. The large gaping wound in the horse\'s side is a major focus of the painting. Under the horse is a dead, apparently dismembered soldier; his hand on a severed arm still grasps a shattered sword from which a flower grows. On the open palm of the dead soldier is a stigma, a symbol of martyrdom derived from the stigmata of Christ. A light bulb blazes in the shape of an evil eye over the suffering horse\'s head (the bare bulb of the torturer\'s cell). Picasso\'s intended symbolism in regards to this object is related to the Spanish word for lightbulb; \"bombilla\", which is similar to the word \"bomba\" for bomb in Spanish.\n\tThe shape and posture of the bodies express protest. Picasso uses black, white, and grey paint to set a somber mood and express pain and chaos. Flaming buildings and crumbling walls not only express the destruction of Guernica, but reflect the destructive power of civil war. The newspaper print used in the painting reflects how Picasso learned of the massacre. The broken sword near the bottom of the painting symbolizes the defeat of the people at the hand of their tormentors.</string>
    <string name="title_4_8">Guernica</string>

    <string name="theory_4_2">By the winter of 1909/10 Picasso\'s pictorial language had already become increasingly hard to decipher. He was steadily divesting his paintings of mere likeness, not that this was synonymous with a progressive elimination of the subject: his paintings were becoming more abstract but not entirely so. \n\tIn 1910 Picasso and Fernande Olivier spent a summer vacation in Cadaques, and this was where Woman with Mandolin originated. Having emerged from an Early Cubist phase which seemed, in part, expressive, Picasso was now in the throes of Analytical Cubism, a period during which he invested surface ornament with intrinsic value. In this picture, the characteristic fragmentation of form is carried to almost unre-cognizable lengths. Only the mandolin is comparatively easy to identify in the lower reaches of the composition.\' Both the outlines of the figure and its internal drawing have been broken down into interpenetrative geometrical elements. The coloration is dominated by brown tones paling to beige. Blue-grey accents, often directly juxtaposed with dark, structural lines, imbue the painting with facet-like plasticity.\n\tDespite the considerable problems of interpretation which this picture presents and would present in even greater measure were it not for the title, Girl with Mandolin is by no means totally devoid of realism. Picasso was concerned, not with the mimetic reproduction of a woman holding a musical instrument, but with the objective nature of his subject - hence, for all the painting\'s tendencies toward formal dissolution, its unmistakable retention of plasticity.</string>
    <string name="title_4_2">Girl with Mandolin</string>

    <string name="theory_4_1">Demoiselles d\'Avignon (The Young Ladies of Avignon, and originally titled The Brothel of Avignon) is a large oil painting created in 1907 by the Spanish artist Pablo Picasso (1881–1973). The work portrays five nude female prostitutes from a brothel on Carrer d\'Avinyó (Avinyó Street) in Barcelona. Each figure is depicted in a disconcerting confrontational manner and none are conventionally feminine. The women appear as slightly menacing and rendered with angular and disjointed body shapes. Three figures on the left exhibit facial features in the Iberian style of Picasso\'s native Spain, while the two on the right are shown with African mask-like features. The racial primitivism evoked in these masks, according to Picasso, moved him to \"liberate an utterly original artistic style of compelling, even savage force.\"\n\tIn this adaptation of Primitivism and abandonment of perspective in favor of a flat, two-dimensional picture plane, Picasso makes a radical departure from traditional European painting. This proto-Cubist work is widely considered to be seminal in the early development of both Cubism and Modern art. Les Demoiselles was revolutionary and controversial, and led to wide anger and disagreement, even amongst his closest associates and friends. Matisse considered the work something of a bad joke, yet indirectly reacted to it in his 1908 Bathers with a Turtle. Braque too initially disliked the painting, yet perhaps more than anyone else, studied the work in great detail. And effectively, his subsequent friendship and collaboration with Picasso led to the Cubist revolution. \n\t The work was seen publicly for the first time at the Salon d’Antin in July 1916; an exhibition organized by the poet André Salmon. It was at this exhibition that André Salmon, who had already mentioned the painting in 1912 under the title Le Bordel philosophique, gave the work its present title Les Demoiselles d’Avignon (in preference to the title originally chosen by Picasso, Le Bordel d’Avignon) to lessen its scandalous impact on the public.</string>
    <string name="title_4_1">Les Demoiselles</string>

    <string name="theory_4_11">José Victoriano (Carmelo Carlos) González-Pérez(March 23, 1887 – May 11, 1927), better known as Juan Gris, was a Spanish painter and sculptor born in Madrid who lived and worked in France most of his life. Closely connected to the innovative artistic genre Cubism, his works are among the movement\'s most distinctive.\n\tBorn in Madrid, Gris studied mechanical drawing at the Escuela de Artes y Manufacturas in Madrid from 1902 to 1904, during which time he contributed drawings to local periodicals. From 1904 to 1905, he studied painting with the academic artist José Moreno Carbonero. It was in 1905 that José Victoriano González adopted the more distinctive name Juan Gris.\n\tGris began to paint seriously in 1911 (when he gave up working as a satirical cartoonist), developing at this time a personal Cubist style. In A Life of Picasso, John Richardson writes that Jean Metzinger\'s 1911 work, Le goûter (Tea Time), persuaded Juan Gris of the importance of mathematics (numbers) in painting. Gris started painting persistently in 1911 and exhibited for the first time at the 1912 Salon des Indépendants (a painting entitled Hommage à Pablo Picasso).\n\tHe appears with two styles. In one of them a grid structure appears that is clearly reminiscent of the Goûterand of Metzinger\'s later work in 1912. In the second the grid is still present but the lines are not stated and their continuity is broken. Their presence is suggested by the heavy, often triangular, shading of the angles between them. Both styles are distinguished from the work of Picasso and Braque by their clear, rational and measurable quality.</string>
    <string name="title_4_11">Juan Gris</string>

    <string name="theory_4_10">The papier collé, invented by Georges Braque and Pablo Picasso in 1912, found a rich and complex expression in the 1914 works of Gris. In conception, his papiers collés are closer to paintings than are the sparely drawn compositions of his forerunners; unlike them Gris covers the whole surface with pasted papers and paint. In works such as Breakfast, Gris\'s use of printed papers is more literal than theirs: the wood-grained fragments usually follow some of the contours of a table and are therefore integral to the composition; and his perspectival cues are relatively legible and precise. His superimposed drawings of domestic objects, fragmented yet softly modeled and most often seen from above, combine to create a more representational pictorial composition than those of Braque and Picasso.\n\tDespite these observations, Breakfast is full of troubling contradictions. The striped wallpaper background spills across the table; certain objects (a glass on the left, a bottle in the upper right) appear as ghostly presences; the coffeepot is disjointed; the tobacco packet is painted and drawn in photographically realistic trompe l\'oeil, but its label is real. Thus, while aspects of domestic comfort are captured in this image, Gris also raises many subjective and objective questions about how reality is perceived.</string>
    <string name="title_4_10">Breakfast</string>

    <string name="theory_4_7">In 1906 Juan Gris traveled to Paris, where he met Pablo Picasso and Georges Braque and participated in the development of Cubism. Just six years later, Gris too was known as a Cubist and identified by at least one critic as \"Picasso’s disciple.\" Gris’s style draws upon Analytic Cubism—with its deconstruction and simultaneous viewpoint of objects—but is distinguished by a more systematic geometry and crystalline structure. Here he fractured his sitter’s head, neck, and torso into various planes and simple, geometric shapes but organized them within a regulated, compositional structure of diagonals. The artist further ordered the composition of this portrait by limiting his palette to cool blue, brown, and gray tones that, in juxtaposition, appear luminous and produce a gentle undulating rhythm across the surface of the painting.\n\tGris depicted Picasso as a painter, palette in hand. The inscription, \"Hommage à Pablo Picasso,\" at the bottom right of the painting demonstrates Gris’s respect for Picasso as a leader of the artistic circles of Paris and as an innovator of Cubism. At the same time, the inscription helped Gris solidify his own place within the Paris art world when he exhibited the portrait at the Salon des Indépendants in the spring of 1912.</string>
    <string name="title_4_7">Portrait of Pablo Picasso</string>

    <string name="theory_5_0">Dada or Dadaism was an art movement of the European avant–garde in the early 20th century (1916 – 1920). Dada in Zurich, Switzerland, began in 1916, spreading to Berlin shortly thereafter, but the height of New York Dada was the year before, in 1915. The term anti-art, a precursor to Dada, was coined by Marcel Duchamp around 1913 when he created his first readymades. Dada, in addition to being anti-war, had political affinities with the radical left and was also anti-bourgeois.\n\tMany Dadaists believed that the \'reason\' and \'logic\' of bourgeoisie capitalist society had led people into war. They expressed their rejection of that ideology in artistic expression that appeared to reject logic and embrace chaos and irrationality. For example, George Grosz later recalled that his Dadaist art was intended as a protest \"against this world of mutual destruction.\" Dada ignored aesthetics. If art was to appeal to sensibilities, Dada was intended to offend.\n\tSurrealism is a cultural movement that began in the early 1920s, and is best known for its visual artworks and writings. The aim was to \"resolve the previously contradictory conditions of dream and reality.\" Artists painted unnerving, illogical scenes with photographic precision, created strange creatures from everyday objects and developed painting techniques that allowed the unconscious to express itself.\n\tSurrealism developed out of the Dada activities during World War I and the most important center of the movement was Paris. From the 1920s onward, the movement spread around the globe, eventually affecting the visual arts, literature, film, and music of many countries and languages, as well as political thought and practice, philosophy, and social theory.\n\t Pop art is an art movement that emerged in the mid-1950s in Britain and in the late 1950s in the United States. Pop art presented a challenge to traditions of fine art by including imagery from popular culture such as advertising, news, etc. In pop art, material is sometimes visually removed from its known context, isolated, and/or combined with unrelated material. The concept of pop art refers not as much to the art itself as to the attitudes that led to it. \n\tPop art employs aspects of mass culture, such as advertising, comic books and mundane cultural objects. It is widely interpreted as a reaction to the then-dominant ideas of abstract expressionism, as well as an expansion upon them. And due to its utilization of found objects and images it is similar to Dada. Pop art is aimed to employ images of popular as opposed to elitist culture in art, emphasizing the banal or kitschy elements of any given culture, most often through the use of irony. It is also associated with the artists\' use of mechanical means of reproduction or rendering techniques.</string>
    <string name="title_5_0">Modern Art</string>

    <string name="theory_5_4">Andy Warhol (August 6, 1928 – February 22, 1987) was an American artist who was a leading figure in the visual art movement known as pop art. His works explore the relationship between artistic expression, celebrity culture and advertisement that flourished by the 1960s. After a successful career as a commercial illustrator, Warhol became a renowned and sometimes controversial artist. The Andy Warhol Museum in his native city, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, holds an extensive permanent collection of art and archives. It is the largest museum in the United States dedicated to a single artist.\n\tWarhol\'s art used many types of media, including hand drawing, painting, printmaking, photography, silk screening, sculpture, film, and music. He was also a pioneer in computer-generated art using Amiga computers that were introduced in 1984, two years before his death. He founded Interview Magazine and was the author of numerous books, including The Philosophy of Andy Warhol and Popism: The Warhol Sixties. He managed and produced the Velvet Underground, a rock band which had a strong influence on the evolution of punk rock music. He is also notable as a gay man who lived openly as such before the gay liberation movement. His studio, The Factory, was a famous gathering place that brought together distinguished intellectuals, drag queens, playwrights, Bohemian street people, Hollywood celebrities, and wealthy patrons.\n\tWarhol has been the subject of numerous retrospective exhibitions, books, and feature and documentary films. He coined the widely used expression \"15 minutes of fame\". Many of his creations are very collectible and highly valuable. The highest price ever paid for a Warhol painting is US $105 million for a 1963 canvas titled \"Silver Car Crash (Double Disaster)\". A 2009 article in The Economist described Warhol as the \"bellwether of the art market\". Warhol\'s works include some of the most expensive paintings ever sold.</string>
    <string name="title_5_4">Andy Warhol</string>

    <string name="theory_5_3">Campbell\'s Soup Cans, which is sometimes referred to as 32 Campbell\'s Soup Cans, is a work of art produced in 1962 by Andy Warhol. It consists of thirty-two canvases, each measuring 20 inches (51 cm) in height × 16 inches (41 cm) in width and each consisting of a painting of a Campbell\'s Soup can—one of each of the canned soup varieties the company offered at the time. The individual paintings were produced by a printmaking method—the semi-mechanized screen printing process, using a non-painterly style. Campbell\'s Soup Cans\' reliance on themes from popular culture helped to usher in pop art as a major art movement in the United States.</string>
    <string name="title_5_3">Campbell\'s Soup Cans</string>

    <string name="theory_5_8">Salvador Domingo Felipe Jacinto Dalí i Domènech, 1st Marqués de Dalí de Pubol (May 11, 1904 – January 23, 1989), known as Salvador Dalí , was a prominent Spanish surrealist painter born in Figueres, Catalonia, Spain.\n\tDalí was a skilled draftsman, best known for the striking and bizarre images in his surrealist work. His painterly skills are often attributed to the influence of Renaissance masters. His best-known work, The Persistence of Memory, was completed in August 1931. Dalí\'s expansive artistic repertoire included film, sculpture, and photography, in collaboration with a range of artists in a variety of media.\n\tDalí employed extensive symbolism in his work. For instance, the hallmark \"melting watches\" that first appear in The Persistence of Memory suggest Einstein\'s theory that time is relative and not fixed. The idea for clocks functioning symbolically in this way came to Dalí when he was staring at a runny piece of Camembert cheese on a hot August day.\n\tDalí attributed his \"love of everything that is gilded and excessive, my passion for luxury and my love of oriental clothes\" to an \"Arab lineage\", claiming that his ancestors were descended from the Moors.\n\tDalí was highly imaginative, and also enjoyed indulging in unusual and grandiose behavior. His eccentric manner and attention-grabbing public actions sometimes drew more attention than his artwork, to the dismay of those who held his work in high esteem, and to the irritation of his critics.</string>
    <string name="title_5_8">Salvador Dali</string>

    <string name="theory_5_2">The Persistence of Memory (Spanish: La persistencia de la memoria; Catalan: La persistència de la memòria) is a 1931 painting by artist Salvador Dalí, and is one of his most recognizable works. The well-known surrealist piece introduced the image of the soft melting pocket watch. It epitomizes Dalí\'s theory of \"softness\" and \"hardness\", which was central to his thinking at the time.\n\tIt is possible to recognize a human figure in the middle of the composition, in the strange \"monster\" that Dalí used in several contemporary pieces to represent himself – the abstract form becoming something of a self-portrait, reappearing frequently in his work. The figure can be read as a \"fading\" creature, one that often appears in dreams where the dreamer cannot pinpoint the creature\'s exact form and composition. One can observe that the creature has one closed eye with several eyelashes, suggesting that the creature is also in a dream state. The iconography may refer to a dream that Dalí himself had experienced, and the clocks may symbolize the passing of time as one experiences it in sleep or the persistence of time in the eyes of the dreamer. The orange clock at the bottom left of the painting is covered in ants. Dalí often used ants in his paintings as a symbol of decay. The craggy rocks to the right represent a tip of Cap de Creus peninsula in north-eastern Catalonia. Many of Dalí\'s paintings were inspired by the landscapes of his life in Catalonia. The strange and foreboding shadow in the foreground of this painting is a reference to Mount Pani.</string>
    <string name="title_5_2">The Persistence of Memory</string>

    <string name="theory_5_6">Hugo Ball was born in Pirmasens, German Empire, and was raised in a middle-class Catholic family. He studied sociology and philosophy at the universities of Munich and Heidelberg (1906–1907). In 1910, he moved to Berlin in order to become an actor and collaborated with Max Reinhardt. At the beginning of the First World War he tried joining the army as a volunteer, but was denied enlistment for medical issues. After witnessing the invasion of Belgium, he was disillusioned saying: \"The war is founded on a glaring mistake, men have been confused with machines\". Considered a traitor in his country, he crossed the frontier with his wife and settled in Zürich. Here, Ball continued his interest in anarchism, and in Mikhail Bakunin in particular; he also worked on the book of Bakunin translations, which never got published. Although interested in anarchist philosophy, he nonetheless rejected it for its militant aspects, and viewed it as only a means to his personal goal of enlightenment. \n\tIn 1916, Hugo Ball created the Dada Manifesto, making a political statement about his views on the terrible state of society and acknowledging his dislike for philosophies in the past claiming to possess the ultimate Truth. The same year as the Manifesto, in 1916, Ball wrote his poem \"Karawane,\" which is a poem consisting of nonsensical words. The meaning however resides in its meaninglessness, reflecting the chief principle behind Dadaism. Some of his other best known works include the poem collection 7 schizophrene Sonette, the drama Die Nase des Michelangelo, a memoir of the Zürich period Flight Out of Time: A Dada Diary, and a biography of Hermann Hesse, entitled Hermann Hesse. Sein Leben und sein Werk (1927).</string>
    <string name="title_5_6">Hugo Ball</string>

    <string name="theory_5_7">Ball’s poem Karawane considered by many Ball disciples as his finest poem, is composed of made up words coupled with existing sounds. Many academics discredit and treat “Karawane” and other sound poems as avant-garde nothingness, full of squeaks and shrieks. This, however, misses the value of the work. Ball’s sound poetry was performance based, entertaining, and it created an emotional language experienced through performance. His new language came alive when Ball moved on the small cabaret stage. The sounds stood for something that each audience member created differently in their minds.</string>
    <string name="title_5_7">Karawane</string>

    <string name="theory_5_1">Drowning Girl (also known as Secret Hearts or I Don\'t Care! I\'d Rather Sink) is a 1963 painting with oil and synthetic polymer paint on canvas by Roy Lichtenstein. Utilizing the conventions of comic book art, a thought bubble conveys the thoughts of the figure, while Ben-Day dots echo the effect of the mechanized printing process. It is one of the most representative paintings of the pop art movement, and part of the Museum of Modern Art\'s permanent collection since 1971. The painting is considered among Lichtenstein\'s most significant works, perhaps on a par with his acclaimed 1963 diptychWhaam!. Drowning Girl has been described as a \"masterpiece of melodrama\", and is one of the artist\'s earliest images depicting women in tragic situations, a theme to which he often returned in the mid-1960s.\n\tThe painting shows a teary-eyed woman on a turbulent sea. She is emotionally fraught, seemingly from a romance. She declares that she would rather sink in the ocean than call Brad. This is revealed through a thought bubble that provides the narrative element: \"I Don\'t Care! I\'d Rather Sink — Than Call Brad For Help!\" The narrative element highlights the clichéd melodrama, while its graphics reiterate Lichtenstein\'s theme of painterly work depicting mechanized reproduction. The work is derived from a 1962 DC Comics panel, while also borrowing from Hokusai\'s The Great Wave off Kanagawa and from elements of modernist artists Jean Arp and Joan Miró. It is one of several Lichtenstein works that mentions a hero named Brad who is absent from the picture. Both the graphical and narrative elements of the work are significantly cropped from the original source image.</string>
    <string name="title_5_1">Drowning Girl</string>

    <string name="theory_5_5">Just what is it that makes today\'s homes so different, so appealing\? is a collage by English artist Richard Hamilton. It measures 10.25 in (260 mm) × 9.75 in (248 mm). The work is now in the collection of the Kunsthalle Tübingen, Tübingen, Germany. It was the first work of pop art to achieve iconic status.\n\tJust what is it that makes today\'s homes so different, so appealing\? was created in 1956 for the catalogue of the exhibition This Is Tomorrow in London, England in which it was reproduced in black and white. In addition, the piece was used in posters for the exhibit. Hamilton and his friends John McHale and John Voelcker had collaborated to create the room that became the best-known part of the exhibition. \n\tThe Dutch pop band Shine, led by ex-Fatal Flowers frontman Richard Janssen, used this image on the back of their three EPs (Popmusic, This is It and Are Friends Electric\?), which were released in the spring of 1995.</string>
    <string name="title_5_5">Just what is it</string>

    <string name="model_name_0">metaio/mlisa.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_0">Da Vinci-Mona Lisa </string>
    <string name="size_data_0">Image is in original size</string>

    <string name="model_name_1">metaio/the_last_supper_model.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_1">Da Vinci-Last Supper </string>
    <string name="size_data_1">Original image is 8 times bigger</string>

    <string name="model_name_2">metaio/sistine_madona.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_2">Raphael-Sistine Madonna </string>
    <string name="size_data_2">Image is in original size</string>

    <string name="model_name_3">metaio/birth_of_venus.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_3">Botticelli-Birth of Venus</string>
    <string name="size_data_3">Image is in original size</string>

    <string name="model_name_4">metaio/basket_of_fruit.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_4">Caravaggio-Basket of Fruit</string>
    <string name="size_data_4">Image is in original size</string>

    <string name="model_name_5">metaio/sick_baccus.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_5">Caravaggio-Sick Baccus</string>
    <string name="size_data_5">Image is in original size</string>

    <string name="model_name_6">metaio/boy_basket_of_fruit.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_6">Caravaggio-Boy With a Basket </string>
    <string name="size_data_6">Image is in original size</string>

    <string name="model_name_7">metaio/samson_delila.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_7">Rubens-Samson and Delilah </string>
    <string name="size_data_7">Image is in original size</string>

    <string name="model_name_8">metaio/hunt.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_8">Rubens-Hippopotamus Hunt</string>
    <string name="size_data_8">Image is in original size</string>

    <string name="model_name_9">metaio/philosopher.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_9">Rembrandt-Philosopher in Meditation </string>
    <string name="size_data_9">Image is in original size</string>

    <string name="model_name_10">metaio/nightwatch.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_10">Rembrandt-Nightwatch</string>
    <string name="size_data_10">Original image is 4 times bigger</string>

    <string name="model_name_11">metaio/las_meninas.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_11">Velázquez-Las Meninas</string>
    <string name="size_data_11">Original image is 4 times bigger</string>

    <string name="model_name_12">metaio/haystacks.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_12">Monet-Haystack</string>
    <string name="size_data_12">Image is in original size</string>

    <string name="model_name_13">metaio/water_lilies.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_13">Monet-Water Lilies</string>
    <string name="size_data_13">Original image is 2 times bigger</string>

    <string name="model_name_14">metaio/bal.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_14">Renoir-Bal</string>
    <string name="size_data_14">Original image is 2 times bigger</string>

    <string name="model_name_15">metaio/boating_party.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_15">Renoir-Boating Party</string>
    <string name="size_data_15">Original image is 2 times bigger</string>

    <string name="model_name_16">metaio/belliellis.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_16">Degas-Bellielli Family</string>
    <string name="size_data_16">Original image is 2 times bigger</string>

    <string name="model_name_17">metaio/starry_night.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_17">Van Gogh-Starry Night</string>
    <string name="size_data_17">Image is in original size</string>

    <string name="model_name_18">metaio/dr_gatchet.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_18">Van Gogh-Portrait of Dr. Gatchet</string>
    <string name="size_data_18">Image is in original size</string>

    <string name="model_name_19">metaio/scream.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_19">Edvard Munch-Scream</string>
    <string name="size_data_19">Image is in original size</string>

    <string name="model_name_20">metaio/pope_inocent.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_20">Bacon-Study after Portrait of Pope Innocent X</string>
    <string name="size_data_20">Image is in original size</string>

    <string name="model_name_21">metaio/fate_animals.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_21">Franz Marc-Fate of the Animals</string>
    <string name="size_data_21">Image is in original size</string>

    <string name="model_name_22">metaio/twittering_machine.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_22">Franz Marc-Twittering Machine</string>
    <string name="size_data_22">Image is in original size</string>

    <string name="model_name_23">metaio/senecio.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_23">Paul Klee-Senecio</string>
    <string name="size_data_23">Image is in original size</string>

    <string name="model_name_26">metaio/bottle_and_fishes.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_26">Braque-Bottle and Fishes</string>
    <string name="size_data_26">Image is in original size</string>

    <string name="model_name_25">metaio/violin_and_candlestick.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_25">Braque-Violin and Candle</string>
    <string name="size_data_25">Image is in original size</string>

    <string name="model_name_28">metaio/guernica.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_28">Picasso-Guernica</string>
    <string name="size_data_28">Original image is 7 times bigger</string>

    <string name="model_name_24">metaio/girl_mandolin.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_24">Picasso-Girl with a Mandolin</string>
    <string name="size_data_24">Image is in original size</string>

    <string name="model_name_27">metaio/portrait_picasso.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_27">Gris-Portrait of Pablo Picasso</string>
    <string name="size_data_27">Image is in original size</string>

    <string name="model_name_30">metaio/persistance_memory.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_30">Dali-Persistence of Memory</string>
    <string name="size_data_30">Image is in original size</string>

    <string name="model_name_29">metaio/drowning_girl.obj</string>
    <string name="image_data_29">Lichtenstein-Drowning Girl</string>
    <string name="size_data_29">Original image is 2 times bigger</string>

    <string name="title_activity_show_theory">showTheory</string>
    <string name="title_activity_renaissance_levels">renaissance_levels</string>
    <string name="title_activity_baroque_levels">baroque_levels</string>
    <string name="title_activity_impressionism_levels">impressionism_levels</string>
    <string name="title_activity_expressionism_levels">expressionism_levels</string>
    <string name="title_activity_cubism_levels">cubism_levels</string>
    <string name="title_activity_modern_levels">modern_levels</string>

</resources>
